<?xml version="1.0" encoding="US-ASCII" standalone="no"?><noticias>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>New York prison break: New possible sightings - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 15:23:24</data>
        <autor>Holly Yan and Steve Almasy, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)After 16 days on the run, the escaped killers could be anywhere. But authorities are honing in on a rural "hot spot" in southwestern New York. The latest possible sighting of fugitives Richard Matt, 48, and David Sweat, 35, came in Allegany County, just north of the Pennsylvania border. That's where a witness reported seeing two men along a railroad line Saturday in the town of Friendship, New York State Police said. While state police called the report an "unconfirmed sighting," a law enforcement source briefed on the prisoner investigation told CNN there was a credible sighting of Matt and Sweat near Friendship. The Allegany County Sheriff's Office said a tipster led investigators to a set of tracks in the area. Authorities were following the tracks to try to determine whether they're from the two escapees. If Matt and Sweat were indeed in Friendship, that means they somehow traveled more than 300 miles southwest of Dannemora, New York, where they had escaped from the Clinton Correctional Facility.  The sudden swarm of attention on Friendship has bewildered the rural town of 2,000 people. Gary Baker, 80, said he's terrified of the possibility that the killers are in the area. Normally, Baker is a caretaker at the town's Maple Grove Cemetery, right next to his home. But authorities blocked off the cemetery as search helicopters hovered overhead. Now, Baker sits alone in his home, with all his doors locked and a rifle in his lap. "I think they're really serious that they've seen somebody," Baker said. "I just hope they catch them." Emergency services radio traffic monitored by CNN indicated large numbers of police had moved into the area. At one point, responding officers were asked to maintain radio silence. Jenn Schanz, a reporter for CNN affiliate WIVB in Buffalo, tweeted that she was asked to leave the search area because state police said it was a "hot spot."  Allegany County isn't the only area investigators have received tips from. Last weekend, witnesses reported seeing two suspicious men in Steuben County, about 45 miles east of Friendship, state police said. "Witnesses spotted two men on June 13 walking near the Gang Mills railyard on Rita's Way in the town of Erwin," police said "The next day, two men with the same description were spotted walking along County Route 115 in the town of Lindley, heading toward the Pennsylvania border." The unconfirmed sightings came from two separate people, police spokesman Beau Duffy said. State police have sent investigators to the areas to conduct interviews. On Saturday, police urged anyone living in the Allegany County area along the New York-Pennsylvania border to be on alert for Matt and Sweat, who many say have nothing to lose. "Do not approach," officials warned. "Both are considered to be very dangerous." Who are Richard Matt and David Sweat? So dangerous, in fact, that the U.S. Marshals Service added Matt and Sweat to its list of the 15 most wanted fugitives. The list "is reserved for the worst of the worst," said U.S. Marshals Service Director Stacia Hylton. "There is no question David Sweat and Richard Matt fall into this category." A $50,000 reward is being offered for information leading to either man's capture. As many as 800 law enforcement officers have participated in the manhunt, which has cleared nearly 200 abandoned buildings, hundreds of occupied homes and more than 600 miles of rural trails, officials said. "We're not going anywhere," New York State Police Maj. Charles Guess said. "Our plan is to pursue these men relentlessly until they are in custody." State police have asked hunters and homeowners with surveillance cameras to check their footage all the way back to June 6, the day of the prison break, for any unusual activity. The search has stretched to Canada and Mexico, with wanted posters of the escaped killers distributed at both borders.  New details have emerged about the relationships between the convicts and prison tailor shop instructor Joyce Mitchell, who has been charged with aiding in escape. Joyce Mitchell, 51, is behind bars, accused of providing the escapees with sneaking hacksaw blades, chisels, drill bits, a punch and other contraband before they broke out. Authorities have said Matt had a sexual relationship with Mitchell. No court date has been set for Mitchell, who has pleaded not guilty to the two charges brought against her and has been talking to authorities. If convicted, she could face up to eight years behind bars. Her husband Lyle, who also worked in the prison's tailoring block, feels betrayed by what happened, his attorney says. Opinion: What will happen to the prison tailor? But the prosecutor said Wednesday that Lyle Mitchell didn't know about the prisoners' escape plan before it happened and wasn't aware of his wife's relationships with the inmates. And in another development, a corrections officer was placed on administrative leave as part of the investigation into the escape, the state corrections department said. The officer's name was not released. The district attorney declined to comment but said the corrections officer was male. Escape puts staff-inmate relationships in the spotlight CNN's Shimon Prokupecz, Deborah Feyerick, Poppy Harlow, David Shortell, Linh Tran, Joe Sutton, Randi Kaye and Danelle Garcia contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/21/us/new-york-prison-break/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>CNN's &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/profiles/deborah-feyerick-profile"&gt;Deborah Feyerick&lt;/a&gt; reports that a law enforcement source says they believe there was a credible sighting of the escaped killers in New York. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150617130442-richard-matt-david-sweat-progression-split-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/06/20/credible-sighting-of-fugitives-wivb-sot.cnn</video>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Al Jazeera journalist arrested in Berlin - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 10:31:13</data>
        <autor>Mariano Castillo and Sara Mazloumsaki, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)The Qatar-based Al Jazeera network is calling on German authorities to release a journalist arrested in Berlin and wanted in Egypt. Ahmed Mansour, a senior journalist for the network, was arrested at the airport in Berlin as he tried to board a flight to Qatar, Al Jazeera reported Saturday. An Egyptian court convicted and sentenced Mansour in absentia on charges of torturing a lawyer in Cairo's Tahrir Square in 2011. He was sentenced to 15 years. In a statement, Mansour said the German officers told him the arrest was at the request of Egyptian authorities. After the journalist was sentenced last year, Egypt did ask the international police body Interpol to seek Mansour's arrest, but according to Al Jazeera, the request was denied. "I informed [the German police] that the global police organization has rejected Egypt's request and that I have this document from the Interpol to prove that I am not wanted in any charge," Mansour said. The journalist said the charges and his conviction were "fabricated," and Al Jazeera characterized them as "a flimsy attempt at character assassination" against Mansour. German police confirmed that a journalist was arrested at the Tegel airport on Saturday afternoon, but declined to give the detainee's name. Germany's federal police cited an Interpol request as the reason for the arrest. It is not the first time Egyptian authorities have gone after Al Jazeera journalists. Three journalists -- Peter Greste, Mohamed Fahmy and Baher Mohamed -- spent more than a year behind bars. They were arrested in Egypt in December 2013, accused of supporting the Muslim Brotherhood and broadcasting footage that portrayed the regime falsely with the intention of bringing it down. They have consistently denied the charges or any ties to the Muslim Brotherhood, saying they were only doing their jobs. Earlier this year, Greste was freed and deported to his native Australia, and Fahmy and Mohamed were granted bail pending a retrial. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/20/europe/germany-al-jazeera-arrest-egypt/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Al Jazeera journalist Peter Greste tells CNN's Hala Gorani why he's refusing to return to Egypt for a re-trial.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150620225327-ahmed-mansour-a-senior-al-jazeera-arabic-tv-journalist-was-arrested-and-detained-at-berlin--large-169.png</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/25/wrn-egypt-journalist-peter-greste-intv.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>After Charleston shooting, worship returns to Emanuel - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 16:10:06</data>
        <autor> Ralph Ellis, Ray Sanchez and Susanna Capelouto, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)The site of a horrific mass killing became a house of worship again. Hundreds filled the pews of historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, South Carolina, for services Sunday morning. "The doors of the church are open," declared the Rev. Norvel Goff during prayers. "No evildoer, no demon in hell or on Earth can close the doors of God's church," he proclaimed. They sang hymns, prayed and remembered the nine church members shot to death Wednesday night during Bible study. One of the victims was the church's pastor, the Rev. Clementa Pinckney. His seat behind the podium was shrouded in black cloth and uniformed police officers were present in the side aisles. Overcoming evil with faith in God was a theme throughout the service. "It's by faith that we are standing here and sitting here," Goff said. "Lots of folks expected us to do something strange and break out in a riot. Well, they just don't know us," he said as the congregation stood and cheered.  Goff thanked the people of Charleston and South Carolina. "We have shown the world how we as a group of people we can come together and pray and work out things that need to be worked out." Right now, he said, the focus needs to be on the grieving families of the nine victims. "There is a time and place for everything," he said. But Goff did call for action "Let's not get it twisted. We're going to pursue justice, we're going to be vigilant and we're going to hold our elected officials accountable to do the right thing," he said. "The blood of the Mother Emanuel Nine requires us to work until not only justice is served in this case, but for those who are still living on the margin of life." Goff thanked Gov. Nikki Haley, who was present at the service, and everyone who sent condolences, brought flowers and made donations. He also thanked the FBI and local police. "And finally I want to say thank you to law enforcement. I have no problem in doing that. I want to thank them," he said. U.S. Sen. Tim Scott and the mayors of Charleston and North Charleston were also among the worshippers. Outside the church, where a makeshift memorial covers the entire sidewalk, crowds gathered in the street and listened to the service through loudspeakers. At 10 a.m., churches around Charleston -- nicknamed the Holy City because it has so many houses of worship -- rang their bells in solidarity with Emanuel AME. The bell at St. Matthew's Lutheran Church rang 81 times -- 9 times for each victim. On Sunday night, a unity chain will be held on the 13,200-foot Arthur Ravenel Jr. Bridge. Organizers hope to attract enough people to hold hands and stretch from Charleston to the town of Mount Pleasant on the other side of the Cooper River. "When something this horrendous happens this close to home, you are compelled to do something," event coordinator Dorsey Fairbairn said on Facebook.  Two law enforcement officials have said Dylann Roof of Lexington, South Carolina, admitted to shooting and killing the people he'd sat with for Bible study at the historically black church. Roof, 21, is white, and all the victims were black. He told investigators he did it to start a race war, according to one of the officials. The church area remained a crime scene, and thus off limits to church members, until Charleston police released it Saturday. On Friday, Roof appeared at a bond hearing. Families of the victims addressed him and said they forgave him. That message was echoed by Arthur Hurd, husband of victim Cynthia Hurd. He's in the Merchant Marine and arrived in Charleston on Saturday. "This is all surreal, but what I can say to that young man is that in time I will forgive you," Hurd told CNN affiliate WCIV. "I won't move past this, but I will forgive you. But I hope for the rest of your life, however long or short that may be, you stop and play that tape over and over and over again in your head and see the sheer terror and pain you put purely innocent people through. ..." "I would love to hate you but hate's not in me. If I hate you I'm no better than you." People angry about the killings took to the streets Saturday. In Charleston, hundreds joined the March for Black Lives. The group began the march in total silence, walking to Emanuel AME Church from a nearby park, and stopped outside the church to lay flowers at the makeshift memorial. Once marchers passed the church, the group filled Charleston's iconic King Street, usually packed with tourists this time of year. Many carried signs of support for the victims of the Charleston shooting and the black community: "STILL WE RISE," "Hand in Hand," "Do the right thing," "Black Lives Matter." The march ended with a rally outside the historic Daughters of the Confederacy building.  "That terrorist did not win. He wanted to invoke terror and fear in our community, but we are not for that," an organizer said to the crowd. "We are standing up together, arm in arm. ... We will not bow down, but we will stand up." Despite the sweltering heat, a large crowd filled the front grounds of the South Carolina Capitol in Columbia calling for the Confederate flag to be removed. "Take it down, take it down," chanted the crowd, filled with people of all races and ages holding signs. One woman's sign said, "Love breeds love, hate breeds hate." Another man's sign said, "Remove my ancestors sign." Organizers of the event, the South Carolina Progressive Network, estimated between 1,500 and 1,700 people attended.  Investigators are looking at a website featuring a racist manifesto that mentions Charleston as the "historic" target of an attack and displays images of Roof. The 2,000-word text explains the writer's philosophy of white superiority, saying the Trayvon Martin case "truly awakened me" and that "I chose Charleston because it is most historic city in my state, and at one time had the highest ratio of blacks to Whites in the country." Motive has become the biggest question as state and federal investigators work on the case -- and statements and photos on the website match what investigators have determined so far. Martin's parents, Sybrina Fulton and Tracy Martin, addressed the gunman's assertion. Their son was killed by in 2012 by a neighborhood watch volunteer who was acquitted. "The Trayvon Martin movement was not created to incite hate or further racial divide, but rather birthed to raise awareness to the social injustices that exist across America with regards to senseless gun violence against our young black and brown boys; the movement also focuses on the growing disparities in the lack of prosecution of the actual perpetrators," they said in a statement. Sadness, shock, rage and resilience CNN's Martin Savidge and Catherine Shoichet contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/21/us/charleston-church-shooting-main/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Hundreds of people filled the pews of historic Emanuel African Methodist Episcopal Church in Charleston, South Carolina, for services Sunday morning.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150621093030-emanuel-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/21/charleston-emanuel-ame-church-memorial-service.cnn</video>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Attackers open fire on child's birthday party in Detroit; 10 people shot - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 14:18:08</data>
        <autor>Faith Karimi and Janet DiGiacomo, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)Attackers fired semiautomatic weapons at a child's birthday party in Detroit, killing one person and wounding nine others, authorities said. A 20-year-man died in the Saturday night shooting, CNN affiliate WXYZ reported. Nine other people -- three women and six men -- suffered injuries, WXYZ said. It's a "miracle" no child was injured at the party, which was held at a basketball court, Detroit Assistant Police Chief Steve Dolunt told the affiliate. About 400 people attended the party, but there are no leads so far, and witnesses are not cooperating, Dolunt said. "There's kids out here. I'm livid. ... There's not any excuse why no one is talking," he told WXYZ. "Man up or woman up, whatever, and tell us what's going on." Dolunt said police are looking for the owner of an abandoned red car found across the street whose occupants they believe were shot. Authorities will continue their investigations Sunday. CNN's George Montgomery contributed to this report</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/21/us/detroit-birthday-party-shooting/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Police say attackers fired semiautomatic weapons at a child's birthday party in Detroit, killing one person and wounding nine others. CNN affiliate &lt;a href="http://www.wxyz.com/news/5-people-shot-on-detroits-west-side-one-fatal" target="_blank"&gt;WXYZ&lt;/a&gt; has more.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150325082152-social-gfx-cnn-logo-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/21/charleston-emanuel-ame-church-memorial-service.cnn</video>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Philadelphia block party shooting victims include baby - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 15:29:30</data>
        <autor>Kevin Conlon, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)Ten people, including three children, were shot at a Philadelphia cookout and block party Saturday night. According to Philadelphia police incident report, witnesses said "that two unknown black males had fired (at the crowd) with a shotgun at least once and then (drove) down the street in a gold or silver four door sedan and fired several more shots, possibly with a handgun." "It looks like they just fired randomly into the street and hit whoever was in their way," said Philadelphia police Lt. John Walker. "It's a terrible situation." Victims' injuries included gunshot wounds to the leg and face. The youngest victim, an 11-month-old, was shot in the neck, according to CNN affiliate KYW. All victims were taken to local hospitals and listed in stable condition, according to Philadelphia police. CNN's Sheena Jones contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/21/us/philadelphia-block-party-shooting/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Ten people, including three children, were shot at a Philadelphia block party and cookout Saturday night.  </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150621112304-philadelphia-shooting-kyw-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/us/2015/06/21/charleston-emanuel-ame-church-memorial-service.cnn</video>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>James Holmes trial: tears, then prosecution rests - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 01:03:43</data>
        <autor>Sara Weisfeldt, Michael Martinez and Ana Cabrera, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Centennial, Colorado (CNN)The capital murder trial of James Holmes reached a turning point when the prosecution rested its case this week, calling as its last witness a victim who survived the movie theater massacre but lost her pregnancy and her small daughter. Her powerful testimony capped two months of work for the jury thus far. It was also a week where the jurors themselves were in the news -- again. Another was dismissed. Next week jurors will begin hearing the defense's case. Holmes, 27, a one-time promising doctoral student in neuroscience, has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity to 165 counts alleging he killed 12 people and injured 70 more at a midnight showing of the new Batman movie "The Dark Knight Rises" in Aurora, Colorado, in 2012. Here are five things from the week's proceedings on one of the worst mass killings in U.S. history.  The prosecution rested Friday with heartbreaking testimony from survivor Ashley Moser. Moser, then 25, was pregnant and was shot 3 times. She lost her pregnancy and is now paralyzed. She also lost her 6-year-old daughter, Veronica Moser-Sullivan, the youngest of the slain victims. The mother stood up to try to leave the theater and got shot, falling on top of Veronica. Friend Kaylan Bailey, then 13 and a frequent babysitter to Veronica, tried to give Veronica CPR, but couldn't get to Veronica's chest because the mom was lying atop her daughter, and the mom couldn't be moved. Moser sobbed under questioning by District Attorney George Brauchler. "As soon as I stood up, I just remember getting hit in the chest, and I remember falling and landing on top of her," Moser testified. Do you know what hit you in the chest, the prosecutor asked. "No, I thought it was a firework at the time," Moser said. When you fell on top of her, did you feel her moving, the prosecutor asked. "No." Did you feel her breathing? "No." Could you get off of her? "No," Moser said. "I tried, but I couldn't move." Moser remembered people crying and screaming, and she was very scared. Her next memory was of being carried out of the cinema. She is still recovering from the catastrophic injuries. "I got shot three times, one in my thigh, twice in my back," Moser said. "One went all the way through my chest, and the other one ricocheted off my shoulder blade and into my spinal cord." Moser has permanent nerve pain in her legs. She can't walk but has regained some feeling in her upper body. She has no control over bodily functions and relies on an oxygen tank to breath at night due to the removal of the upper left lobe of her lung, she testified. The prosecutor then asked her about learning of her daughter's death. "It was Thursday night or Friday morning when this happened. Were you told on Sunday finally something about your daughter?" the prosecutor asked. "Yes, I was," Moser said. What were you told? Moser paused and sobbed before the jury: "I was told that she didn't make it, that she had passed away," she said. Through tears, Ashley then identified her daughter in a picture taken from her kindergarten graduation.  Immediately following Moser's testimony, District Attorney Brauchler declared to the court: "Your honor, the people of the state of Colorado rest." The culmination of proceedings Friday marked day 35 and week eight of the trial. In all, the prosecution called more than 200 witnesses. They included a wide variety of law officers, crime scene investigators, first responders, and University of Colorado Anschutz Medical Campus professors and students who knew Holmes in the neuroscience program. Four psychiatrists testified about their professional opinions about Holmes' mental health and sanity: two court appointed doctors who did psychiatric evaluations and two others who treated Holmes in the months before the shooting. Holmes' ex-girlfriend and friends also testified. Various records custodians from stores told the jury about where Holmes purchased weapons and protective gear and ammunition. Woven throughout all these witnesses was emotional testimony from survivors. Their accounts were devastating and hauntingly consistent in terms of what happened that night and the lasting physical and emotional injuries. The prosecution never let too much time go by before calling a survivor to testify -- seeming to want to keep the emotion in play for the jurors as the weeks wore on. The defense starts presenting its case on Thursday.  A total of five jurors have been dismissed in the past two weeks. That contrasts to the first six weeks of the trial, when there were no juror dismissals. That leaves 12 jurors and seven alternates for what could be two more months of trial. The gender breakdown is 14 women and five men. Of the 19, the judge and the attorneys are the only ones who know which are actual jurors and which are alternates. Here's a quick summary of how the juror dismissals: * June 9: The judge excused three jurors after a fourth juror reported overhearing one of them talking about the case during a court break. The fourth juror revealed two such incidents. * Monday, June 15: A woman juror become the fourth dismissal after she changed her story to the judge about how her brother-in-law became involved in a mishap. One day, she told the judge her relative was in an accident. Another day, she told the judge he was involved in a shooting. Arapahoe County Judge Carlos Samour was concerned that the juror may have known about the nature of her relative's incident on June 10 but withheld information from the court to remain a juror. The judge also expressed concern for the juror's emotional well-being. In a twist, this removed juror returned to the courtroom as an observer on Thursday. The judge warned the jurors that they are not allowed to speak with the former juror. And the judge also warned the former juror that she is not allowed to speak to the jurors or the media. * Wednesday, June 17: Another woman juror was dismissed for not being forthcoming to the judge about recognizing a witness, Maria Carbonell, who testified on May 5. Carbonell's son attends the school where the juror works. "I don't believe you were completely forthcoming and candid with me when Ms. Carbonell testified," the judge told the juror being ousted. "I think Ms. Carbonell recognized you and she told us about it. And then it's when she told us about it that you and I ended up having a conversation on May 6, so I'm going to go ahead and release you." On the other hand, a male juror asked to speak to the judge this week because he recognized one of the witness as someone he plays fantasy football with and has hung out with now and then. The juror assured the judge that knowing the witness would not interfere with his ability to be fair and impartial, so the judge thanked the juror and continued with the trial with that juror still on the job.  For the first time, jurors saw a tape of James Holmes purchasing two of the weapons used in the movie theater massacre. The two videos came from store surveillance cameras, captured about a month apart and just weeks before the shooting in the post-midnight minutes of July 20, 2012. The first video shows Holmes walking into Gander Mountain in Thornton, Colorado, on June 7, 2012. With short brown hair and in dark clothing, he strolled up to the firearms counter and left 30 minutes later with an MMP 15 sport rifle, three bushmaster magazines, a shotgun sling, and some .223 ammunition that cost $968.38, according to the receipt from that day. Lee McGinley, the sales associate who helped Holmes that day, explained all firearms purchases have to be approved by the Colorado Bureau of Investigation, or CBI, which can take just a few minutes or several hours. Holmes passed a background check, McGinley told the court. The second video, from at Bass Pro Shops in Denver, provided a grainy, shorter account of Holmes on July 6, 2012: Sales associate Brian Pennington testified he was behind the counter attending a customer in front of him. It was Holmes, wearing a tan shirt, a tan hat and light colored pants. The video does not show the customers' face, nor Holmes' hair, which he had reportedly already dyed orange by then. That orange-red hair later became a signature of Holmes' mug shot, making him resemble the cartoon villain Joker in the Batman serials. Pennington didn't remember Holmes specifically, but he did remember a problem with the sales transaction. "At the time of the purchase, the first credit card was declined," Pennington told the court. Prosecutors used that piece of information to connect the video with a receipt from the time of purchase showing Holmes' MasterCard had been declined, twice. He eventually used a Visa to pay the $1,149.24 bill and left with several items, including a Glock handgun, ammunition, and cleaning supplies.  Sobs cut through the silence in the courtroom as shooting survivor Jamison Toews testified about the moment he realized 6-year-old Veronica Moser-Sullivan had no pulse. Toews was in the theater with his pregnant girlfriend, Ashley Moser, also Veronica's mother. The trio was joined by two teenage girls who babysat Veronica earlier in the day. One of those babysitters was Toews' cousin, Kaylan Bailey. Toews described being hit in the face with buckshot even before he realized what was happening. "My head was gushing blood," he recalled. He scanned the theater and saw people rushing for the exit and running down the stairs. One person dragged his leg "as if he were wounded," Toews said. "And I saw the shooter shooting toward those people," Toews said. Moments later, he realized Veronica was on the ground with her mother atop her. The mother couldn't move. Toews became emotional as he described when police arrived and he yelled "that I have a pregnant woman that's down, a 6-year-old that's down." "They immediately came down to help us," Toews recounted. "They checked (emotional pause) they checked their pulses (pause), and Ashley had a pulse and Veronica did not." Through tears, Toews testified how a first responder carried Veronica down the stairs, put her on the floor and started CPR. But Toews was forced to leave the theater without the small girl to help get her mother to the hospital. Later, he learned Veronica did not survive. Neither did the couple's unborn baby. CNN's Sara Weisfeldt and Ana Cabrera reported from Colorado. Michael Martinez wrote and reported from Los Angeles.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/20/us/james-holmes-trial-aurora-colorado-movie-theater-shooting/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>James Holmes' family spoke out Monday saying "their hearts go out to the victims &amp;amp; their families." Casey Wian reports.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/120723084633-holmes-mugshot-t3-entertainment.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/bestoftv/2012/07/23/exp-erin-holmes-family-speaks-out.cnn</video>
        <categoria>us</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>UK army parachutist rescues team mate after chute fail - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-20 17:46:02</data>
        <autor>Laura Smith-Spark and Lucy Pawle, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>London (CNN)A parachutist with the British Army's Red Devils stunt team rescued a fellow jumper in a midair drama after his parachute failed during a stunt jump. The dramatic scene played out above the heads of anxious spectators at the Whitehaven Airshow in Cumbria, northern England. A statement on the Facebook page for the airshow said one of the parachutists' chutes failed to deploy properly. Brian Sherwen, an official photographer for the event who witnessed the incident, said he saw the two men "dropping through the sky." He was able to see exactly how the rescue unfolded through a videographer's powerful zoom lens. "It was obvious the top jumper was wrapping his legs around the ropes of the parachutist below -- his legs were carrying the weight of the man below and his tangled parachute," he said. "There was quite a lot of flailing of the legs, then the bottom guy stopped struggling and just held his legs straight down. "The top guy was obviously in control and was trying to find a safe area to land. They were falling down at least twice as fast as the other people who were jumping with them." The two men didn't land where they were supposed to for the display but in a nearby marina busy with big yachts with masts, Sherwen said. "They've done very well to get down in the open water," he said. He spoke to a member of the team afterward and said he seemed quite blas&#233; about the death-defying maneuver. "They acted like it was just another day at the office," he said. "We can confirm that the Red Devil parachutists are both safe &amp; sound," the airshow's Facebook statement said. "For the first time in 25 years they had a parachute fail. One team member caught his team-mate &amp; brought him into Queens Dock. Our safety procedures worked perfectly &amp; a huge thank you to Whitehaven Marina for getting them out of the water so quickly." A subsequent statement confirmed that the team members were "both fine" following their splash landing. Another witness, Tom Davies, told CNN: "We are all just relieved no one was hurt, but the team member saved his buddy without doubt. He is a hero." </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/20/europe/uk-red-devils-parachute-rescue/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>A parachutist with the British Army's Red Devils stunt team rescued a fellow jumper in a midair drama after his parachute failed during a stunt jump.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150620112727-parachute2-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/20/red-devils-parachute-incident-sot-parker.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Man drives into crowd in Austria, kills 3 - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-20 17:19:22</data>
        <autor>Greg Botelho and Deborah Bloom, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)Three people have died and dozens more are injured after a man drove into a crowd -- on purpose, the local government says -- Saturday in the Austrian city of Graz. The 26-year-old male driver intentionally used his vehicle as a weapon, the Graz City Council said in a statement. Roman Sommershsacher, a spokesman for the Austrian city's government, said the man drove through Graz's inner city -- including into a place where cars are not normally allowed -- trying to hit people. One of the three fatalities is a child. At least 34 more people suffered injuries, Sommershsacher said, including ten seriously and one in critical condition. The driver -- described as an Austrian citizen with Serbian roots -- has been arrested, officials said at a Saturday afternoon press conference. The officials added that they don't know the man's motive but do not believe it has anything to do with terrorism. Photos from the scene showed a mangled bike and what appeared to be a body draped by a white sheet. Located in Styria province in southeastern Austria, Graz is that country's second-most populous city. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/20/europe/austria-graz-car-hits-crowd/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>A man who purposely drove his car into a crowd killed three and injured dozens in Graz, Austria, according to authorities.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150620115433-austria-car-attack---restricted-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/20/red-devils-parachute-incident-sot-parker.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Pope prays before Shroud of Turin - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 14:19:02</data>
        <autor>Don Melvin, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)Pope Francis prayed Sunday before the Shroud of Turin, a strip of cloth that some believe was used for the burial of Jesus Christ. The shroud appears to bear the image of a man who resembles paintings of Christ. "The shroud attracts towards the face and the martyred body of Jesus and at the same time pushes us towards the face of those who suffer or are unjustly persecuted," the Pope said afterward at a Mass in Piazza Vittorio. "It pushes us in the direction of the gift that is Jesus' love."  It was the start of a busy day for the Pope as he made a pastoral visit to the city of Turin, in northern Italy. Later, he spoke with workers gathered in Piazzetta Reale. "A job isn't only necessary for economic reasons but for the human being, for his dignity, his citizenship and for social inclusion," the Pope told those gathered in the square. "Immigration increases competition, but we don't have to blame the migrants because they are victims of inequality, of this throwaway economy and the wars. "It's sad to see the spectacle of this last period, where human beings are treated as goods," the Pope said. He also spoke in support of women's rights and against job discrimination based on gender.  The Pope's schedule called for him to have lunch with prisoners at the Ferrante Aporti penitentiary, named after a 19th-century Italian educator and theologian. He was also slated to meet sick and disabled people at a church, followed by dinner at the residence of the archbishop. Scientists are divided over how the image became embedded in the linen and whether it is really Christ's death shroud. The Shroud of Turin was first heard of around the year 1360, according to the New Advent website. It says the authenticity of the shroud is "taken for granted" by the Holy See. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/21/europe/pope-visits-shroud-of-turin/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Pope Francis prayed in front of the Shroud of Turin, believed by some to be the death shroud of Jesus Christ. CNN's Delia Gallagher reports.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150618084447-02-pope-francis-file-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/21/pope-francis-visits-shroud-of-turin-gallagher-lok.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Egypt: Dog mummies in catacombs estimated in millions - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-20 16:42:20</data>
        <autor>Greg Botelho, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)For centuries, dogs have been humans' loyal, domesticated companions. They've been wild animals, doing what's needed to survive. And in ancient Egypt, they served as bridges to the afterlife, with the hope that they'd intercede with the god Anubis on their owner's behalf. But only now is it becoming known the extent to which dogs served this latter role -- 8 million times over. That is the number of dead animals, most of them dogs, estimated to have laid in the catacombs of Anubis around Saqqara, one of Egypt's most historic and oft-visited sites, according to a group of British researchers. While such mass burials aren't unprecedented, given the numerous animal cults of ancient Egypt, this one's scale makes it unique. "We're very pleased and somewhat surprised by the results," the project's director Paul Nicholson from Cardiff University's School of History, Archaeology and Religion said Saturday. "We hadn't expected that there would be so many animals, and it opens up a new series of questions." One question that experts can at least partially answer is why an Egyptian might have brought an animal, dead or alive, to such a place. Nicholson, who has been studying animal cults since the 1990s, explains that people wouldn't have come simply to kill or even bury an animal so much as allow it to move onto a different plane. A dog, especially, would be a good fit because it might then interact with Anubis, an ancient Egyptian god of the dead depicted with the body of a man and head of a dog or, its close relative, a jackal. "The important thing was to provide a representation of the god with a fitting burial," Nicholson said. "It's not some sort of blood sacrifice. It's a religious act that's done for the best possible motive." The animal's owner would hope that, by doing this, "some good will come to you," the Wales-based Egyptologist noted. "Maybe you're hoping that the animal will help someone in your family who has died recently (so that) Anubis will take care of that (relative)." Just as Egyptians' view of Anubis, and dogs, has been common knowledge for some time, so too have the dog catacombs of Anubis. This includes a map from 1897 that shows their location clearly marked. Still, most of the focus was on temples outside the catacomb. Until, that is, Nicholson's team -- with the support and help from Egypt's Supreme Council of Antiquities and sponsorship from National Geographic -- began working on the Saqqara site around 2009 and began exploring deep inside. They found a series of unadorned tunnels, in some cases filled with animal remains and in other cases cleared out. (Nicholson speculated that some may have been taken out for use in fertilizers, as has been done with other animal remains.) Those that they found were wrapped in bandages and mummified, including some with a resin applied. One shouldn't imagine an ornate King Tut, though: They were likely stacked on top of each other and "survived very badly," Nicholson said. "It would be quite difficult to easily find complete, nicely wrapped mummies," he added. "What you have got is the decayed remains of the mummies." To estimate how many there are, the team took a sample and extrapolated from there how many likely filled up the catacomb. One reason the number is so high is because many of the animals were very small; while there some were mature and likely had full lives, Nicholson speculated that some were "being especially bred for the cult." The catacombs are believed to date from between roughly 750 to 30 B.C., up to the time Egypt's society was interacting more and more with those of Europe, including ancient Greece and Rome. A summary of the Cardiff team's findings was published this week in the journal Antiquity. Nicholson and his co-authors, Salima Ikram and Steve Mills, are now working on a more complete study. And the work continues at the Saqqara site, which includes other animal catacombs and many monuments like the step pyramid of Djoser, as well as in laboratories to discover more about the animal remains, such as patterns of sex and age. "We are very curious about where the animals came from," Nicholson said. "We're learning quite a bit about the Egyptians' interactions with animals. It's an exciting thing." Could Egypt's empty animal mummies reveal an ancient scam? </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/20/africa/egyptian-millions-mummified-dogs/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>An estimated 8 million mummified animals, mostly dogs, were laid in the catacombs of Anubis, a high figure that surprises even veteran Egyptologists.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150620104607-mummified-dog-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/21/pope-francis-visits-shroud-of-turin-gallagher-lok.cnn</video>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Who is the 2,000-year-old 'sleeping beauty'? - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-15 09:52:00</data>
        <autor>Daisy Carrington, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)It was the Queen of Sheba that first drew Louise Schofield -- an archaeologist and former curator at the British Museum -- to the Gheralta plateau in northern Ethiopia. She'd heard tell of a 20-foot stone stele carved with an inscription and a symbol often linked to the biblical queen: a sun and crescent moon. "The story of the Queen of Sheba has a central place in the heart of all Ethiopians, so I became interested in the story myself," she recalls (Sheba is thought to be located in parts of Ethiopia). It was this initial visit that ultimately led her to discover the 2,000-year-old remains of a character she fondly refers to as "sleeping beauty." The grave was discovered at the stone stele, in an area that was once part of the ancient kingdom of Aksum, which today encompasses Ethiopia and Eritrea. Inside, Schofield's team found the skeleton of a woman posed in a resting position, with her chin laid gently on one hand. A Roman-era bronze mirror was placed before her face. The corpse was surrounded with glass vessels (to catch the tears of the dead), as well as a bronze cosmetics spoon and a lump of kohl eyeliner. "She must have been very wealthy, and probably well-loved to be placed in this position, and judging by all the items of finery around her," surmised Schofield. The dig also uncovered several other graves, all of which had several bodies buried beneath. In some, she found the remains of large warriors clad who each wore an iron bangle. "We think they were warriors from a battle," she says. The unusual find suggests trade between Rome and Aksum started at least 200 years earlier than previously believed. As the dig is less than a month old, there's still a lot of information yet to come in about this restful lady. A bone expert wasn't able to ascertain her age at the time of death because the pelvis -- which usually provides a close approximation -- had been consumed by termites. Schofield hopes that analysis of the teeth will provide some answers. "There was something very personal about the way she was lying," Schofield says. The remains were also found surrounded by clay containers that likely contained food or drink (these have also been sent off for analysis). "The food, drink and cosmetics were all presumably left for her to use in the afterlife. She was pre-Christian and that's how people buried their dead then," says Schofield. Shofield has a bit of the Midas touch when it comes to extraordinary finds. She also recently uncovered a Roman-era perfume flask in the same cemetery, although by chance. The archaeologist is also the director of London-based NGO The Tigray Trust, and the item was first brought to her attention by a local farmer she knew through the organization. "I had been showing around a member of the Peace Corps who had been working in a nearby town (around the site), and we'd been out in the blazing sun for 8 hours, when a farmer I knew said his friend found something old, and he'd been keeping it for me," she recalls. "I was apologizing to the Peace Corps guy. I told him, 'it could be an old coffee pot, but you never know, it could be the Queen of Sheba's perfume flask.'" Read more: Divers discover underwater lemur graveyard Read more: The dinosaur that ate sharks for breakfast </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/africa/sleeping-beauty-2000-year-old-remains/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Anthropologists have uncovered the grave of a 2,000 year old skeleton curled up on her side. Who was this' well-loved' lady?</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612143534-ethiopia-archaeology-excavation-sleeping-beauty-large-169.jpeg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/21/pope-francis-visits-shroud-of-turin-gallagher-lok.cnn</video>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Australia: A society that brought in tight gun controls - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-19 16:35:44</data>
        <autor>Laura Smith-Spark, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)It doesn't have to be this way, President Barack Obama said. "At some point, we as a country will have to reckon with the fact that this kind of mass violence does not happen in other advanced countries. It doesn't happen in other places with this kind of frequency. It is in our power to do something about it." The U.S. has been shaken by multiple high-profile mass shootings in the past few years -- an elementary school in Connecticut, a movie theater in Colorado, two separate incidents at Fort Hood, Texas, and now the church shooting in Charleston, South Carolina. But can something be done? Australia, a country that in some ways shares the United States' frontier mentality and history as part of the British empire, implemented sweeping gun-control measures that have been successful for nearly two decades. So, theoretically it's possible, but "the power to do something about it" in the U.S. is limited by factors that are deeply rooted in its culture and baked into its founding document. Any change to the Second Amendment of the U.S. Constitution ("...the right to bear arms shall not be infringed") ultimately would require the approval of three-fourths (38) of the states -- forgetting the political hurdle of Congress' even proposing such a measure. The National Rifle Association, with more than 5 million members and a powerful lobbying arm in Washington, reflects a vast interest group in a nation where there are nearly as many firearms (more than 300 million) as there are people. Gun control: Change is possible -- and fast What happened in Australia? Gun violence was bad. A decade of gun massacres had seen more than 100 people shot dead. The last straw was an incident at a popular tourist spot at Port Arthur, Tasmania, in April 1996, when a lone gunman killed 20 people with his first 29 bullets, all in the space of 90 seconds. This "pathetic social misfit," to quote the judge in the case, achieved his final toll of 35 people dead and 18 seriously wounded by firing a military-style semiautomatic rifle. What happened next? Only 12 days after the shootings, in John Howard's first major act of leadership and by far the most popular in his first year as Prime Minister, his government announced nationwide gun law reform. Uniform legislation agreed to by all states and territories -- the national government has no control over gun ownership or use -- specifically addressed mass shootings: Rapid-fire rifles and shotguns were banned, gun owner licensing was tightened and remaining firearms were registered to uniform national standards. How did Australia do it? In two nationwide, federally funded gun buybacks, plus large-scale voluntary surrenders and state gun amnesties both before and after Port Arthur, Australia collected and destroyed more than a million firearms, perhaps a third of the national stock, according to Professor Philip Alpers of the University of Sydney, who is editor of gunpolicy.org. No other nation had attempted anything on this scale. The national government also banned the importation of new automatic and semiautomatic weapons. And the buyback was paid for by a special one-off tax on all Australians. What was the political fallout? It wasn't without cost to John Howard. Political interest groups among his conservative base raised hell, and the move met strong resistance from some in rural areas. His party's coalition partner in those areas suffered in subsequent elections. But the majority of Australians, shocked by the mass killing, backed action. And it worked. Multiple homicides involving gun are exceptionally rare, none have been remotely as bloody and random as the Port Arthur massacre, and none have involved the sort of weapons whose importation was banned. What exactly happened to murder and mass killing? In the years after the Port Arthur massacre, the risk of dying by gunshot in Australia fell by more than 50% -- and stayed there. A 2012 study by Andrew Leigh of Australian National University and Christine Neill of Wilfrid Laurier University also found the buyback led to a drop in firearm suicide rates of almost 80% in the following decade. In the 19 years since the announcement of legislation specifically designed to reduce gun massacres, Australia has seen no mass shootings. As Howard wrote in an opinion piece for the New York Times in 2013, "Today, there is a wide consensus that our 1996 reforms not only reduced the gun-related homicide rate, but also the suicide rate." Can America follow it? The gun culture in the United States is a powerful factor that can't be ignored. Howard acknowledged those key differences in an interview with CNN's Christiane Amanpour in 2013. "I don't come here with any lectures," he said. Australia started with a much lower gun death rate, he said, and "we don't have constitutional guarantees in relation to these things." "However," he added, "that doesn't alter the fact that our murder rate using guns has fallen and there's not much doubt in my mind that it's the availability of guns that causes such a high rate of murder using weapons." How other countries deal with massacre nightmare </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/19/world/us-australia-gun-control/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Former Australian Prime Minister John Howard discusses the legislative action he took after a mass shooting. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/130326152552-exp-australia-john-howard-amanpour-00021517-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/international/2013/03/26/exp-australia-john-howard-amanpour.cnn</video>
        <categoria>world</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>India ties itself in knots over International Yoga Day - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-21 05:56:45</data>
        <autor>Tiffany Ap, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Hong Kong (CNN)The Sanskrit word "yoga" may mean union but, for some in India, yoga has never been more divisive. June 21 marks the first ever International Day of Yoga, an event that's driven by Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi. A faithful yoga practitioner for years, Modi persuaded the United Nations last year to devote a day to the ancient discipline. This Sunday, around 45,000 people in New Delhi attempted to break the world record for the single largest session of yoga. Modi was present at the public demonstration which included civil servants and students, many of whom were ordered to practice their chaturangas and downward dogs ahead of the event. Similar yoga events are being held all around the globe. Modi's worldwide yoga vision, however, isn't sitting well with everyone. Some in India's Muslim community, which makes up around 15% of the population, say they are feeling marginalized.  Although it's viewed mainly as a form of physical exercise in the west, yoga carries religious associations in India. Muslim associations like the influential Islamic scholars group, Jamiat Ulema I Hind, the All India Muslim Personal Law Board and several prominent imams have taken issue with a common sequence called "sun salutations" which they interpret as sun worship. "Om" which is often chanted in yoga classes is also a sacred sound in Dharmic religions. "We do not know how it has been approved by the UN," Abdul Rahim Qureshi, an All India Muslim Personal Law Board spokesperson told CNN. "A true Muslim cannot take part in yoga. The yoga is made compulsory for the primary and high school students. What are they teaching little children? The government should not take up this cause of yoga and impose them on non-Hindus." To ease the backlash, Indian authorities reassured the public that sun salutations would be dropped from the event, though chanting "om" would still be a part of it. Government officials also pointed out that out of 177 sponsoring nations, 47 are from the Organization of Islamic Countries.  Objections from India's Muslim community are not the only point of strain. Although yoga's roots are undeniably Indian, much of what is practiced today is an Americanized version. There are over 25 million people who practice yoga in the United States alone, by far the largest single market, and that's grown 33% since 2009, according to a study from the Sports and Fitness Industry Association. It's a multi-billion dollar market that extends to $420 yoga leggings and $140 mats. The vigorous push from the Indian government has given new life to a debate over who owns yoga and what defines it. Newly-appointed Indian minister for yoga Shripad Yesso Naik said it's something India wants to reclaim from the west. "We're trying to establish to the world that it's ours," Naid told the Washington Post. Noah Maze, a LA-based yoga teacher however believes the yoga practiced today is something new. "While it has roots in practices from India, and certainly we can find lists of asanas in some of the medieval alchemical texts of hatha yoga, what is practiced today really is an innovation and evolution of what was practiced traditionally," Maze said. "I would expect that Indian yogis may be looking at yoga's explosion internationally, and feeling a sense of ownership and entitlement to the practices and concepts," Maze added.  Striking the right balance between respecting the tradition's roots and its new incarnations as yoga's popularity surges is a question many practitioners grapple with. "I quiver a bit when hearing of the lax usage of the word 'yoga' these days," said Tim Feldmann, an Ashtanga teacher who co-founded the Miami Life Center with his yogi wife Kino Macgregor. "A yoga studio down the road from us here in Miami offers 'yoga booty ballet'. In my ear, that is obviously an only commercial aspirational use of the word." For Macgregor, it's a mindset much more than the ability to twist like a pretzel and she emphasizes it's open to anyone. "This brilliance does not belong to any one culture," she said. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/19/world/international-yoga-day/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>BKS Iyengar, the man who brought yoga to the masses, has died at the age of 95. CNN's Sumnima Udas shares his story.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150621123723-02-modi-yoga-day-2106-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2014/08/21/lok-udas-india-yoga-guru-bks-iyengar-dies.cnn</video>
        <categoria>world</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>This 'eco-stove' does more than cook your dinner - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-01-30 10:56:06</data>
        <autor>Lauren Said-Moorhouse and Florence Obondo, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Every week, African Start-Up follows entrepreneurs in various countries across the continent to see how they are working to make their business dreams become reality. Follow the show on Twitter. (CNN)In Uganda, more than 28 million people in the country are without electricity. To put that into perspective, the entire population of the beautiful landlocked east-central African nation is less than 38 million people. To tackle energy poverty, many entrepreneurs are increasingly devising innovative solutions to explore feasible alternative power options. One of them is Rose Twine. Having grown up in both urban and rural areas of Uganda, Twine knew first hand the challenges faced by many homes when it came to cooking a simple meal. A passionate environmentalist, she decided to do something about it. In 2009, she teamed up with her brother to found their Kampala-based company with their flagship product: the "eco stove." The siblings' green oven uses a type of volcanic rock combined with solar power to act as the fuel for the kitchen appliance. Cook food, charge your phone "The whole point was to ... reduce deforestation, as well as the chores involved in finding firewood for the local person who can't access electricity or gas," explains Twine. The stove has an internal air system that helps heat up the volcanic rocks, which are ready to cook when they turn bright red in color. When the device is switched off, the rocks cool and return to their natural state until the next use. Meanwhile, solar panels on the appliance charge up and help provide additional heat to the stove. Alternatively, Twine explains, the appliance can also be used to provide an additional light source, charge cell phones, play a radio or even iron clothes through steaming. At the moment, the most common solid fuels for cooking and heating homes in Uganda are firewood and charcoal, both of which release thick, acrid smoke into the household. This exposes residents to a number of respiratory health problems -- the World Health Organization estimates that 4.3 million people die annually as a result of hazardous household air pollution. As the Ugandan capital of Kampala continues to flourish more people are choosing to relocate to the city. But an increasing population also means more man-made health factors. Societal problems include extra trash and traffic, which in turn add to the worsening air pollution. Outside of the city, in rural areas, the once green and fertile forests are disappearing at an alarming rate. Deforestation has seen the country lose two thirds of its forests between 1990 and 2005 making it harder for villagers to find wood for burning. Twine hopes her product will provide users with immediate environmental, social, health and economic benefits once they have upgraded their existing kitchens with her eco-alternative. Part businesswoman, part eco-warrior She says: "Everybody says I want (the eco stove) because charcoal is expensive, firewood is hard to find, electricity is very expensive and its not reliable." Surrounded by countless families facing these hardships of accessing sustainable energy everyday, Twine made it her mission to provide a reliable fuel source through her social enterprise startup. It's a vision that has proved fairly popular as more Kampala residents adopt this eco-friendly way of cooking. But Twine explains it usually requires a live demonstration of the product to clinch the sale. "This is a new innovation in the continent that a lot of people need more understanding. It's not something that you can go on TV and say 'this a stove here that will solve all your cooking challenges.' No! "That's why we are always cooking beans (outside the store). You need a lot of stuff on site to be able to demonstrate for anybody who comes in, because it's not something somebody is going to read about it and say 'a stone that cooks and lasts two years' and believe in it. No -- they want to see." It's still early days but the sustainable business has seen some local success in promoting renewable energy -- a cause of great importance to Twine. And it's this passion that spurs the environmental entrepreneur onwards. She explains: "Believe in the dream (and) I think you'll go all the way. Once you believe in it it's easy to transmit the same passion and the same conviction to the person who is going to buy into it. "Once you believe in what you're doing, don't be distracted and don't even be discouraged." Read this: African entrepreneurs get billionaire boost Read this: Bamboo bikes change the face of transport in Ghana Read this: The life-saving backpack that doubles as a light More from African Start-Up </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/01/30/africa/eco-stove-kampala-sustainable-cooking/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Meet the eco-superhero using the sun and volcanic rocks to reinvent cooking in Kampala.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150114125405-spc-african-start-up-eco-stove-00011206-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2014/08/21/lok-udas-india-yoga-guru-bks-iyengar-dies.cnn</video>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>A new mass extinction could be underway - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-20 16:50:20</data>
        <autor>Angad Singh, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)Sixty-five million years ago, the dinosaurs disappeared in what's known as the Earth's fifth mass extinction. Today, a sixth mass extinction could be well underway and humans are the likely culprit, according to new research published in Science Advances. The past five mass extinctions on Earth were caused by large-scale natural disasters like meteors or enormous chains of volcanic eruptions, wiping out between half and 96% of all living species. But the modern mass extinction isn't being caused by a freak act of nature, the researchers say. It's being caused by man-made changes to the environment including deforestation, poaching, overfishing and global-warming, and it's proving to be just as deadly. Recently, species like the Emperor Rat, the Desert Rat Kangaroo, the Yangtze River Dolphin, the Skunk Frog and the Chinese Paddlefish, amongst hundreds of others, are believed to have become extinct. From CNN 2007: Chinese dolphin 'probably extinct' About 477 vertebrate species have been lost since 1900, according to the research by Gerardo Ceballos, a senior ecological researcher at the National Autonomous University of Mexico, and Anthony Barnosky, a biology professor at Berkeley. If humans were not the primary source of these extinctions, there should've only been nine species going extinct during the same time period.  The researchers fear that 75% of the species we know today could be lost in just two generations' time. "We have the potential for making massive change... and the bottom line is that we can't be the generation responsible for wiping out three-fourths of life forms on the Earth," says Barnosky. Biodiversity provides critical functions, including the air in the atmosphere and purifying drinking water -- life as we know it depends on having high levels of species diversity, scientists say. "People think nothing bad will come from species loss, because scientists can't predict exactly how many need to go extinct before the world collapses," says Ceballos. "The problem is that our environment is like a brick wall. It will hold if you pull individual bricks, but eventually it takes just one to make it suddenly fall apart." While extinction is a natural function of life, this is the first time humans are being confronted with species loss at rates that are 1,000 to 10,000 times faster than what is considered the natural rate. Turtle species may go extinct if its last female can't breed  The problem of extinction is becoming very serious, but it is not too late, says Barnosky. "We have the potential of initiating a mass extinction episode which has been unparalleled for 65 million years," says Ceballos. "But I'm optimistic in the sense that humans react -- in the past we have made quantum leaps when we worked together to solve our problems." Barnosky says there are a number of steps people can take: -- Reduce your carbon footprint -- this is to hold back climate change from falling below critical levels and to prevent altered conditions which can ravage fragile ecosystems. -- Never buy products made from threatened or endangered species -- this includes items like ivory, animal furs and rhino horns. -- Eat less meat -- 40% of the Earth is currently under cultivation, and if the lands used to feed livestock were used to grow crops for people, there would be 50 to 70% more calories available for humans to eat, which is enough to feed an additional billion people. It would eliminate the need to clear natural ecosystems like rainforests for farmland. "Little by little people are understanding that we need to change," says Barnosky. "But whatever we decide to do in next 10 to 15 years will decide the future of biodiversity on Earth." Northern white rhinos under guard 24 hours with 1 male left worldwide </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/20/world/mass-extinction-animals/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Researchers have come together to try to save the Yangtze giant softshell turtle and it all relies on the species' last female. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i.cdn.turner.com/cnn/.e/img/4.0/logos/cnn_logo_social.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/05/china-yangtze-turtle-extinction-orig.cnn</video>
        <categoria>world</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>A nude sculpture so small it's 'walking on hair' - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-17 10:03:54</data>
        <autor>Matthew Ponsford, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)She could stand on a strand of human hair, with room to spare. The microscopic polymer statue by South African sculptor Jonty Hurwitz, entitled Trust, measured just 1/100th of a centimeter and had been called the "smallest sculpture ever made." But the world's tiniest woman suddenly disappeared to an unknown location, likely never to be seen again. While she was being photographed through an electron microscope -- the only way to view the minute creation -- Trust vanished, with only a smudged fingerprint left behind by her photographer as a clue. After an hour long search, Hurwitz and the photographer gave in: "It was horror. I remember saying to him: 'You just destroyed or lost the smallest human form that was ever created in history,' said Hurwitz to CNN Ones to Watch. "It was gone." But was it, really?  Hurwitz is an entrepreneur-turned-artist who has applied the same tech wizardry to sculpture that he put into coding a finance site valued at over $500 million. The 45-year-old's "Nano-sculptures" are made from a mysterious resin -- "a big scientific secret", says Hurwitz -- and created through a process called "two-photon lithography." Hurwitz works with a team of nanotechnology engineers at Karlsruhe University, who focus beams of ultraviolet light to "zap" solid the liquid resin, one 3D pixel at a time. The resulting sculptures -- he has also created a statue depicting the classical myth of Cupid and Psyche -- can lie on an ant's head. Put one into the eye of a needle, and it will barely occupy one corner.  The "Nano" project is just one of Hurwitz' science-inspired sculptural experiments. Another one explores the properties of the mathematical constant Pi, presenting an indecipherable, "anamorphic" physical sculpture, whose hidden form becomes clear only when reflected in a cylindrical mirror. And he hints that a forthcoming project will also be influenced by his love of the natural world, but will sit at the opposite end of the scale to his nano-models. Hurwitz, who first made his name as the UK-based co-founder of controversial "payday" loans business Wonga, says he makes visual art with a team, as in traditionally collaborative art forms, such as cinema. He discusses accumulating collaborators as an aggressive start-up accumulates new talent: "I spent a huge amount of time scouring the world for amazing achievements of humanity and contact these people to work with them. For me the creation of an artwork these days is analogous to the creation of a film: for each piece there may 20 people involved, each one brilliant in their field."  Hurwitz makes no secret of his desire to bring together contemporary science and art -- delighting in the fact that his nano-scale and 3D printed pieces depend on cutting edge technology, and would have been unimaginable just 10 years ago. Online, fans response has been overwhelming, he says, and the internet has become his exhibition space. It provides an "epic scale" that brick-and-mortar galleries can't match, he says, and estimates 13 million people have seen his sculptures since they hit the web in November last year. "I love the buzz. I love the buzz when I launch a piece on the Internet and on Google Analytics, you suddenly see society engaging... millions and millions of people engaging." "You put a few images on the internet and just watch society consume, engage and think. With comments and blogs and people saying 'It's not art' and people working out the science behind it and people complaining... I just love that buzz! I love influencing society." There's also another side -- what Hurwitz calls "the traditional side of the geeky art world" -- accusing him of being just an engineer rather than an artist. But he's unapologetic: "A lot of the artistic expression that I bring to the world represents the absolute current moment in human development. Whether it's 3D printing, technology or science, I love to represent the now."  Hurwitz says the creation of the physical artwork is "just the beginning of its lifecycle." So what about the missing woman, whose lifecycle has tragically been cut short? She came back to life during the filming of CNN Ones to Watch (in the video above) -- Trust v.2, her new name, has taken the absent dancer's place. Even still, there are some who think neither dancer was ever there. Invisible to the naked eye, how can we trust this sculpture ever existed beyond the computer screen? For Hurwitz, this mystery gets right to the heart of nano-scale's appeal: "You've got this 'emperor's new clothes' element to this end of the scale spectrum, because you look at these nano-sculptures and there's nothing there, there's an element of me going: 'this sculpture... believe me, it's there.' "At that scale, the sculpture doesn't really exist, or our perception doesn't allow us to perceive its existence. "In a way, it challenges the whole idea of contemporary art, by asking: 'Hang on, a piece of art you can't really see, is it really a piece of art?'" </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/04/07/world/worlds-smallest-sculpture-jonty-hurwitz/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Jonty Hurwitz has worked with nano-physicists to create the sculpture invisible to the human eye</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150327112457-jonty-hurwitz-on-hair-png-large-169.png</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/03/13/spc-ones-to-watch-sculpture-c.cnn</video>
        <categoria>world</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>$3.4 billion worth of art in a corner of Switzerland - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-19 17:41:09</data>
        <autor>Janelle Zara, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Basel, Switzerland (CNN)Art Basel is a behemoth. Think of it as the ultimate superstore of the art market with its endless aisles and swarms of shoppers. The annual event that bears the clich&#233; distinction "mother of all art fairs" is in its 46th year, open for business now through June 21 in its namesake Swiss hometown. It features 300 or so international exhibiting galleries hailing from five continents, and reportedly $3.4 billion worth of art. And if it's anything like it was last year, it will draw a crowd of more than 92,000 people over the course of the week-long event. Insiders will know that by the time the doors open to the public, most of the works have already sold; in the days prior to the official opening, stalwart collectors bearing VIP badges scoop up hundred-thousand- to multi-million-dollar artworks like candy. For everyone else, the display booths are a snapshot of the best of modern and contemporary art. The first thing you'll see entering the Herzog &amp; de Meuron-designed exhibition venue (an aluminium-clad marvel in itself) is Art Basel's Unlimited sector, what the fair describes as a "platform for projects that transcend the limitations of a classical art-show stand." In other words, it's where you'll find everything that is huge, immersive, and Instagram-worthy right now. Just ahead of the entrance, the Berlin-based artist Julius von Bismarck is milling about a makeshift bedroom, tucking himself into bed, at times getting up to sit at his desk and have a glass of red wine. The art of his otherwise mundane performance is that it's happening on the slopes of a giant spinning concrete bowl, where centrifugal forces are all that's holding the furniture in place. "What's your cure for motion sickness?" we asked the artist. "It's best to focus your eyes on one place," he said. "Preferably something inside the bowl." Elsewhere on the Unlimited showroom floor, there are screenings of films by artists including Ed Atkins, Sarah Morris, and Wu Tsang. Photographer Ryan McGinley pasted 500 images on the walls and ceilings of a room to make "YEARBOOK," an all-encompassing, pop-hued collage of sexy young things in the nude. The Scottish artist David Shrigley set up a circle of chairs and easels so that visitors can pull up a seat and sketch "Life Model," a three-meter tall, naked Pinocchio-like sculpture that blinks and urinates intermittently. Despite Unlimited's impressive array, Art Basel's mainstay is its Galleries sector, where 223 exhibitors are showing works from the 20th and 21st century that span painting and sculpture to video and digital. It's where you'll find the more modestly sized works by blue-chip contemporary artists; the Picassos; the Giacomettis; and other top sellers. Other sectors include Parcours, large-scale, site-specific works installed around the historic M&#252;nsterplatz; Statements, a space for emerging artists; and Feature, where the booths are curated presentations on single artists or themes. Outside of the fair, art in Basel is plentiful. In addition to the city's venerable permanent institutions (Paul Gaugin and Marlene Dumas at Fondation Beyeler, as well as Anicka Yi and Bernard Tschumi at Kunsthalle Basel are must-sees), there are myriad satellite fairs and installations that have sprouted throughout town. There's Volta and Liste, two fairs devoted to new and emerging art, not to mention Design Miami/Basel, Art Basel's sister fair. There, the focus is on functional art. The ground floor features Design at Large, an architectural survey of historic and avant-garde dwellings that includes works by the iconic Jean Prouv&#233; and contemporary Atelier Van Lieshout. Upstairs, there's no shortage of mid-century French and Scandinavian design classics, plus new sci-fi inventions. Swarovski's inaugural Designer of the Future presentation features the young new talents Studio Swine, Tom&#225;s Alonso, and Elaine Yan Ling Ng, whose work toys with themes of light and outer space. Swiss luxury watchmaker Audemars Piguet launched a new series of artist commissions that will take place at every art Basel. Robin Meier, a hybrid composer-artist, delivered a living environment: an ecosystem of blinking LEDs, plants, and scientific instruments in a tightly sealed tent, erected in the back of the Volkshaus gallery. The ensuing symphony of light and sound&#8212;cricket recordings, metronomes, and subtle vibrations&#8212;stimulate the fireflies ethereally circulating around the interior, creating a surreal experience for the viewer. Following a high-impact week of sensory overload, it might be the perfect destination for a moment of peace and quiet. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/19/world/art-basel-2015/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Larger than life nudes, LED-lit ecosystems and centrifugal forces were just some of the highlights from the most expensive art fair in the world. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150619112624-art-basel-2-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/03/13/spc-ones-to-watch-sculpture-c.cnn</video>
        <categoria>travel</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>After eight years in slavery, a bittersweet homecoming  - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-19 07:02:24</data>
        <autor>Saima Mohsin, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)The ramshackle house is full of the symbols of time passing. Clocks -- there are at least five of them, none of them telling the right time -- dot the walls. And calendars too, out of date and unmarked; no birthdays, events or memories written into them, just left blank. This is the home of Manee Chanviset, 77, and Samarn Charoensuk, 78, a Thai couple, whose children left them behind long ago. One, their youngest, Maleenu Charoensuk -- nicknamed "Lek" -- had been missing, feared dead, for years. Now they sit in their home, alone. When their children left, times got hard. The parents were reduced to picking through garbage, scavenging to find things that they could sell, so they could eat.  Theirs would have been an untold misery, but for the Labour Rights Promotion Network (LPN), an NGO which found Lek, improbably, stranded on an Indonesian island. They took down information about his family and his hometown, and tracked down his parents. They spoke for the first time in almost eight years, a call arranged by LPN, ears pressed against a borrowed mobile phone. When we arrived at their home it's time to join them as they pick up their son from the airport. They don't have the money to go themselves so another NGO, Stella Maris Seafarer, is taking them. As we walk in, the organization has also brought the couple some provisions, the result of donations. It's an extraordinary turn of events for the elderly couple.  She doesn't have much, but Lek's mother, Manee, buttons up her best, blue silk shirt. It hangs from her thin figure, but she looks so happy -- and nervous. She called Lek's estranged sister for moral support as soon as they heard the government was bringing him back to Thailand, and she is part of the welcoming committee -- an ever-increasing number of family and relatives who have returned to witness his homecoming. But his father won't go to the airport. He says he is not well and too weak, but it seems he is overwhelmed. He breaks down as we set off for the airport, his head in his hands. Tears of joy -- and perhaps disbelief -- that their son is finally coming home. Manee has never even been to the airport before, but this trip is one she's longed for for years. The entire journey she speaks quietly, in a daze. "I never thought this day would come," she says. "My heart is pounding. All I want is to see his face. All I want is to see his face" READ MORE: Seafood from slavery: Can Thailand tackle the crisis in its fishing industry?  When they spot him they cry, and she clings to him, her tiny frame trying to hold him in this moment for as long as she can. "Let's go home... let's go home," she whispers. "Don't you go anywhere again." She takes a good look at him. He is much thinner, and he looks so much older. Lek is in shock at first. He can barely speak but tells his mother, the woman he hasn't seen for eight years, that he didn't think he would ever make it back home. He had disappeared without a trace, without warning. His parents assumed he'd taken a fishing job, like he'd done once before. It's not difficult at all to see why poor young men risk their lives at sea, to try and earn some money to alleviate their extreme poverty. His family's home is a rusty shack of carefully choreographed corrugated iron -- his parents must have built it years ago, before their strength left them.  He tells us how he was tricked onto a boat, at the very beginning of his eight-year ordeal. "I was drunk and they took me to the boat," he recalls. "I told them I wanted to leave but they didn't let me. They hit me and forced me to board. There were so many men." They told him he could go for a three-month trial and that he was free to leave if he didn't like it. He didn't know then that he wouldn't see his home for almost a decade. He says he was on the boat for about seven months before it landed at a port in Indonesia. "Some of us got off to buy some drinks for fellow workers. The captain was so angry he beat us and stabbed me. He abandoned me on an Indonesian island. " "There, I was stuck on land carrying rocks in exchange for food," he says, eyes downcast. READ MORE: Thai PM vows to clamp down on slavery in fishing  He was discovered by LPN only when Indonesian authorities began a clampdown on illegal fishing boats in their waters. Thousands of men from countries across Southeast Asia poured off the boats, telling tales of being trapped at sea. Others were already on islands like Lek's, abandoned with no paperwork. Now he's home, he won't go back, he says. And his parents won't let him. They cling to him. But Lek -- and hundreds of others like him -- is returning home to the same poverty and lack of prospects as they suffered before. They may have just returned but have a long journey ahead; the struggle to settle back in and to find work to feed their families -- in the same conditions that led them, years ago, to being trafficked and forced to work as slaves. How to help: Global hotlines to report suspected cases of human trafficking CNN's Kocha Olarn contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/18/asia/lek-homecoming-thai-kidnapped-fisherman/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Justin Dillon, CEO of Made In a Free World, talks about forced labor in corporate supply chains. CNN's Kristie Lu Stout reports.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150618040326-cfp-thailand-slave-laborer-fisherman-return-home-pkg-00014311-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/14/spc-cfp-thailand-forced-labor-fishing.cnn</video>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Smuggler captain defends trafficking - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16 18:03:10</data>
        <autor>Nima Elbagir, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Burj Mughayzil, Egypt (CNN)On a sandy beach in one of the many inlets dotting Egypt's Mediterranean coastline two men are standing off to one side watching us interview families whose children have been trafficked into Europe. Eventually the taller of them begins to jump in. He starts shouting and explaining why he works on the smuggler boats carrying the human cargo into Europe. "What does the government do for us? We're fishermen but there's nothing to catch." The village, Burj Mughayzil, is essentially a smugglers' village. By their own count 2,000 young men and boys have disappeared. Some as young as 11 and 12, they are lured by the European dream -- but so many of them either end up in Italian jails accused of crewing the smuggling ships or killed in the crossing. We were hoping somewhere on the beach to find a crewman on a smuggling ship, someone who had made the journey and returned. We found two; the tall man and his slimmer friend, who told us they were a ship's mate and a captain. When I asked if they'd talk on camera they agreed. To our surprise they both asked to show their faces and to give their names. CNN has retraced the route traveled by the children from small villages on Egypt's Mediterranean coast, across the sea to Sicily by boat, then making their way to the Italian capital, Rome, where they fall victim to drug and prostitution rings. Thousands of children are risking their lives, falling prey to traffickers, for the dream of a better future for them and their families. Captain Mahmoud and Mohammed told us: "We work the ships. Me and a crew of 15 people. If the [Egyptian] government was helping us in any way we wouldn't be crossing in any way." The trips can take up to nine days on the open seas. The Egyptian Government says it has increased its vigilance along the coastline but still the smugglers are finding ways out. Sometimes he says, 20 boys are crammed on a tiny fishing boat fitted with an onboard motor, so they can be brought out to sea where he and his crew wait on a bigger boat which holds up to 600 people. 'It's risky for the boat and for everyone on it. We could be sentenced to 25 years or be executed if anything happens, God forbid, to anyone on board if it becomes a death trip." He also risks years in an Italian jail on the other side and a 15,000 euro ($17,000) fine for every single person on board. The fine can stretch into the millions, Italian authorities say. It's a risk he knowingly takes. Though, the captain says, leaving him and his men "to rot in jail," is not the solution. "There are big fish and there are small fish. The small fish are the ones who are in Italian jails. The big fish live freely here in Egypt, freely in Italy." Many of the parents claim it is the children themselves who want to go -- but teens we spoke to in Italy say their families expect them to work once they get to Europe and to send money home. Others admit Europe is seen as a way of earning the family much-needed cash but they say they didn't know about the trafficker gangs behind the smuggling routes. Yet others say they were deceived by the smugglers who make empty promises of opportunity across the Med. Authorities in both countries are clear, they say the parents are guilty -- at the very least -- of abandoning their children. The smugglers, Captain Mahmoud says, are very brazen. "We leave here at dusk, dawn, whenever. It doesn't matter if you know you are risking jail anyway. We'll have been paid -- us and the crew - 10,000 Egyptian pounds ($1,300) each. That feeds a crewman's family and kids for a month. Then after that, who knows? Risk it again or die of hunger." Egyptian minors have been flooding into Italy by the thousands according to the Italian Ministry of Labor, taking advantage of Italian laws that grant state protection to those under 18 who arrive in Italy unaccompanied. It's not just the passengers that are underage though; his crew often is as well. Captain Mahmoud says they are pressured by their families. "People here in this village, they're selling their kids. They think, 'we're 10 [people] and we can't find enough to eat. When we're nine, we can eat a little better. If we're eight, we can eat even better still. If two get locked up? Better than we all die together.' All the people in Italian jails? They're the victims of the parents here who can't afford to eat." I asked if they felt a responsibility for the people making the crossing, for those who have died. "How can we not?" he said. "If anything happens to them, it happens to us. If the ship sinks we drown together." His tall friend, Mohammed, talks over him, "How can we not be sad? These are our cousins, our brothers. I still see their faces." At the end of the interview Captain Mahmoud asks again if we're going to broadcast this, if his government will see this. I tell him, yes, we will. Good, he says. Let them hear the truth. Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/16/africa/freedom-project-smuggler-captain/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>CNN's Nima Elbagir reports on thousands of Egyptian children in search of a better life, many of who end up falling victim to drug and prostitution rings. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612105036-7-migrants-journey-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</video>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>The king with 100 wives - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-17 16:45:51</data>
        <autor>Soni Methu, Colin Hancock and Eliza Anyangwe, for CNN </autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)Abumbi II, the 11th fon, or king, of Bafut, Cameroon, has close to 100 wives. They weren't all his to start. According to local tradition, when a fon dies, his successor inherits all his wives and then marries his own queens. "The queens have a great role to play in the fondom," notes Prince Nickson, also of Bafut, noting that it is up to these women behind the man to shape him in his kingly role. "Behind every successful man must be a very successful, staunch woman," says Abumbi's third wife, Queen Constance. "Our tradition has it that when you are king, the elderly wives remain to hand down the tradition to the younger wives, and also to teach the king the tradition because the king had been a prince, not a king." Despite the fact that polygamy is legal in Cameroon, the data shows that there are far fewer polygamous marriages across the African continent. The practice is being challenged by changing values, the spread of the Christian faith, the growing appeal of the western way of life but also the rising costs of having large families. It is against this backdrop that Cameroon's traditional rulers must walk the fine line between two often conflicting cultures. "During colonialism other values came in, of governance, different from the traditional values we had and therefore there is this constant conflict between the traditional values and modern western values," admits Fon Abumbi II, who has ruled Bafut, the largest fondom in the region, for 47 years. "My role is to blend them, to find the way forward so my subjects can enjoy the fruits of development and modernity without destroying their culture. Without a culture, you are not a human being, you are an animal. And therefore the chieftaincy institution is the guarantor of our culture." Though polygamy is often met with criticism in the West, there are some who deem it a valuable tradition. After meeting with Fon Abumbi II, Soni Methu, presenter for CNN's Inside Africa, noted that there was more to the practice than meets the eye: "I understand that we might be quick to judge the lifestyle of the kings, but just like in the United Kingdom, African kingdoms and kings are bound to a rich culture and history. (Practices) like inheritance of all your father's wives is nothing but a moral obligation." She also observed that many of these royals are highly accomplished. On meeting the queens of Fon Ndofua Zofia II of Babungo -- one of Cameroon's youngest traditional rulers -- Methu said: "All his young wives, forced on him by tradition, spoke fluent English in a French-speaking region and were great marketers." It is this seeming contradiction that makes life in the fondom fascinating and confusing. Are they stuck in the past or keeping pace with the present? Fon Zofoa III doesn't think you have to choose. He may have "inherited" 72 wives and more than 500 children after his father's death, but he considers himself a very modern king. "To run a kingdom nowadays in this era, you must be educated because things are moving very fast. Like they used to say, education is light, ignorance is darkness." To meet the fon, or king, of Bafut, as well as his wives, watch the video below: Read more: Making blockbusters in a nation without cinemas Read more: The beekeeping women of Cameroon </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/africa/the-king-with-100-wives-cameroon/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>A kingdom in north-west Cameroon carries on centuries of tradition including polygamy. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/141023161536-last-african-kings-bakary-t3-entertainment.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/08/inside-africa-cameroon-history-a-spc.cnn</video>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Rare double rainbow frames Sydney skyline - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-18 08:36:10</data>
        <autor>Georgia McCafferty, for CNN</autor>
        <corpo>(CNN)It's one of the world's most beautiful cities, but Sydney's sunset was twice as spectacular Wednesday when its beaches, harbor and city skyline were framed by a rare double rainbow. Social media was awash with breathtaking pictures, with the sight literally stopping traffic on the city's streets. A rainbow is a natural phenomenon, formed when sunlight hits falling rain. The rain's tiny drops refract the sun's light into its individual color components and reflect it back at different angles, forming the seven colors of the rainbow. A double rainbow happens when these rays of light are refracted twice. Science aside, there's no arguing with these amazing pictures. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/18/asia/sydney-double-rainbow-stunner/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>It's one of the world's most beautiful cities, but Sydney's sunset was twice as spectacular Wednesday when its skyline was framed by a rare double rainbow. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150618162142-sydney-double-rainbow-full-frame-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/08/inside-africa-cameroon-history-a-spc.cnn</video>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>A day in Russia's military Disneyland - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-18 08:14:40</data>
        <autor>Matthew Chance, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Kubinka, Russia (CNN)A child plays on a war tank. People eat ice cream as they walk past weapons capable of destroying an entire continent. Tens of thousands fill a park full of Russia's latest military weapons: Helicopters. Missiles. Tanks. Boats. Submarines. This is the Disneyland of Russia's military. And right now in Russia, patriotism is in. Its President, Vladimir Putin, opened Patriot Park this week in the latest move to capitalize on the popularity in Russia of the country's recent displays of military force. We arrive after an hour's drive from Russia's capital city, Moscow. We park and take a bus into the main area where a huge exhibition of weapons and technology is on display. Most people here are families. A father is here with his son. "Russia is unbeatable" he says -- and he wants his son to learn it. The air of patriotism is palpable here. As people walk by in Putin T-shirts, we search for Putin souvenirs on sale. No luck. But we do find several shops run by the Russian army. They're quite popular. The shops sell camouflage jackets, fleeces, things like that. And to be honest, they're pretty stylish. It's all part of the effort to keep the military cool -- and reach out to the young. It seems to be working. Elsewhere there's a massive line of people queuing up for free army food. For the price of a wait, you can get a dollop of buckwheat porridge. More traditional fare seems hard to come by, though there are a lot of ice cream stands. We finally find a restaurant and I order a kebab with rice. Patriotic music blares nonstop. A stage hosts different acts: an air force choir singing, funky dancers dressed as Russian soldiers. Some children perform, too. A few foreign military types walk around. A Saudi Arabian Navy officer says they normally buy weapons from Americans -- but they are interested in the innovation here. We see uniforms of Venezuela and Myanmar, too. The park itself is massive. Our photographer takes a bus to a different area where there are live demonstrations. Re-enactments of key Russian and Soviet battles are expected to be a regular part of the Patriot Park experience. Here in the exhibition area, we see a Buk missile launcher on prominent display. This type of weapon is suspected of downing an airliner last year. MH17 crashed last July, killing 298 people on board. Children play happily on the weaponry and people seem to enjoy themselves. And yet there is something brazen, if not insensitive about the display. These are, after all, the tools of war -- killing machines really -- paraded as if they are toys and rides at an amusement park. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/17/europe/russia-military-theme-park-reporters-notebook/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Russian President, hunter and sports enthusiast, Vladimir Putin wears many hats. Matthew Chance reports.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150617154932-08-russia-military-theme-park-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/06/09/putin-profile-chance-orig.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>A day in Russia's military Disneyland - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-18 08:14:40</data>
        <autor>Matthew Chance, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Kubinka, Russia (CNN)A child plays on a war tank. People eat ice cream as they walk past weapons capable of destroying an entire continent. Tens of thousands fill a park full of Russia's latest military weapons: Helicopters. Missiles. Tanks. Boats. Submarines. This is the Disneyland of Russia's military. And right now in Russia, patriotism is in. Its President, Vladimir Putin, opened Patriot Park this week in the latest move to capitalize on the popularity in Russia of the country's recent displays of military force. We arrive after an hour's drive from Russia's capital city, Moscow. We park and take a bus into the main area where a huge exhibition of weapons and technology is on display. Most people here are families. A father is here with his son. "Russia is unbeatable" he says -- and he wants his son to learn it. The air of patriotism is palpable here. As people walk by in Putin T-shirts, we search for Putin souvenirs on sale. No luck. But we do find several shops run by the Russian army. They're quite popular. The shops sell camouflage jackets, fleeces, things like that. And to be honest, they're pretty stylish. It's all part of the effort to keep the military cool -- and reach out to the young. It seems to be working. Elsewhere there's a massive line of people queuing up for free army food. For the price of a wait, you can get a dollop of buckwheat porridge. More traditional fare seems hard to come by, though there are a lot of ice cream stands. We finally find a restaurant and I order a kebab with rice. Patriotic music blares nonstop. A stage hosts different acts: an air force choir singing, funky dancers dressed as Russian soldiers. Some children perform, too. A few foreign military types walk around. A Saudi Arabian Navy officer says they normally buy weapons from Americans -- but they are interested in the innovation here. We see uniforms of Venezuela and Myanmar, too. The park itself is massive. Our photographer takes a bus to a different area where there are live demonstrations. Re-enactments of key Russian and Soviet battles are expected to be a regular part of the Patriot Park experience. Here in the exhibition area, we see a Buk missile launcher on prominent display. This type of weapon is suspected of downing an airliner last year. MH17 crashed last July, killing 298 people on board. Children play happily on the weaponry and people seem to enjoy themselves. And yet there is something brazen, if not insensitive about the display. These are, after all, the tools of war -- killing machines really -- paraded as if they are toys and rides at an amusement park. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.comhttp://cnn.com/interactive/2015/05/world/china-space/</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Russian President, hunter and sports enthusiast, Vladimir Putin wears many hats. Matthew Chance reports.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150617154932-08-russia-military-theme-park-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/06/09/putin-profile-chance-orig.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>How children are trafficked into Europe - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16 15:05:53</data>
        <autor>Nima Elbagir, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Sicily, Italy (CNN)The 13-year-old boy looks off into the distance. He is slight of build with pale, almost yellowy eyes. When you see him you feel as if he has seen far too much already. He is carrying a burden far too heavy for his age -- but despite his ordeal so far, smuggled across continents from Africa to Europe, and now living in a care home, his future could be far worse depending which route he takes next. A CNN investigation spent months retracing the smuggling route from Egypt to Italy. Speaking to social workers and authorities, children and parents, there is evidence that many of the children were smuggled into Italy by the same criminal networks, who once they are in country, use them for illegal activities. The Egyptian government agency charged with advising lawmakers on child protection matters told CNN that they believe in some cases the parents are guilty of trafficking, paying for their own vulnerable children to be smuggled so far from home in the hope of securing the family's future. We were interviewing this Egyptian boy and his friends in the picturesque piazza of a small Sicilian town. They came over to Italy together on an Egyptian smuggler ship. He was 12 at the time and crammed in with hundreds of others. He says his parents paid 35,000 Egyptian pounds (about $4,500) for the privilege, never guessing what it would really be like -- tossed around for nine days, surrounded by vomit, and scared, uncertain what would meet them on shore. I asked him what he would say to all the boys back at home, hoping to follow in his footsteps. He said he would warn them not to come but he also said he knew they wouldn't listen. "Why would they? I didn't," he says. "Everyone does what their mind tells them. They won't take what we say." I asked if, having suffered so much, he'd make the journey again? "What can I do? Yes. The burden back home is still the same." Italian authorities say he is one of more than 1,000 young Egyptians sheltered in 100 Italian care homes now dotting the Sicilian countryside. The cobbled streets and 17th Century architecture is a very long way from the Nile Delta villages many of the boys have come from. I asked one of his friends if he calls his parents and what he tells them about their lives here, and if he's told them how close to death he came. "I tell them nothing, just pleasantries and ask for their prayers. What difference would it make? They need me to make money." These boys tell us their parents went in to debt to raise the fare for their crossing. They saw it as an investment in what they hope will be a better future for the whole family. The children are expected to find work as soon as they can and start sending money home. Here at the care home, that's not possible so thousands of children are disappearing from the Italian social care networks. Italy's Ministry of Labor told us almost 4,000 Egyptian children disappeared from the care system. All the Italian authorities we spoke to who work with these children told us the pressure on the children would be unbearable even for an adult. They fear the consequences to their parents if the smugglers didn't get their money in full, or if the gamble doesn't pay off having sold what little of value they have. The missing children can't work legally. Social workers tell us that too often the children turn to drugs, even prostitution, to get by. Another boy we meet at the home asks me wistfully about Rome, which Italian authorities say is where so many of the disappeared head to. I told him Rome is dangerous for children on their own, especially on the streets. I told him the stories we'd heard from the Egyptian teenagers we'd met in Rome -- the exploitation and the homesickness. The Egyptian children in Rome tell stories of friends selling themselves on street corners -- but they sound suspiciously like they were speaking about themselves. I told him it's better to do it all the legal way and better for him to get an education. He listened politely until I'd finished then told me: "Better to be dead than useless." Dominique Van Heerden, Luca Muzi, Sara Sirgany and Mohamed Kazaz contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/15/europe/freedom-project-misery-trail-children/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>CNN's Nima Elbagir reports on thousands of Egyptian children in search of a better life, many of who end up falling victim to drug and prostitution rings. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150612105036-7-migrants-journey-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</video>
        <categoria>europe</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Fame poses new risk for China's 'magic rabbit' - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-11 00:44:05</data>
        <autor>Shen Lu, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Beijing (CNN)Rarer than a panda, few people knew about the Ili pika until earlier this year when pictures of China's "magic bunny" went viral after being featured in a series of news reports. But now the tiny and endangered mammal is finding out the price of fame. Conservationist Li Weidong, who discovered the species in 1983, lamented the lack of funding for his conservation efforts when first interviewed by CNN in March. READ: Meet China's 'magic rabbit' He's since been able to raise almost $28,000 on a Chinese crowd-funding website, enough to fund his research and conservation efforts for the next year. But Li told CNN this week that the tiny mammal now faces other threats. People have tried to catch the pika, wanting one as a pet. Companies have offered Li funding to catch the pika and then artificially breed them, Li said. "Ili pikas, as alpine animals, can't adapt to the environment at low elevations without special facilities," he said. "Would they survive? Their population is already small enough. Human capture will accelerate the extinction." Fearing that cameras might disturb pikas, Li said he has also turned away a dozen more photographers who hoped accompany him on his field research in the Tianshan mountains.  Native to the Xinjiang region of northwestern China, there are fewer than 1,000 of these creatures living in the Tianshan mountain range in the region, Li said. Li discovered the pika, formally known as Ochotona iliensis, and named it after his hometown, Ili. A year ago, Li spotted and photographed the elusive creature for the first time since the early 1990s. He estimates its numbers have declined by almost 70% since its discovery. In 2008, the animal was listed as endangered by the International Union for Conservation of Nature but there's no official organization or team dedicated studying or protecting it, according to Li. For years, Li has called for Ili Pika to be listed on China's List of Wildlife under Special State Protection -- part of the country's 1988 Wildlife Protection Law. The appeal seems more urgent now as more people have laid eyes on the it, Li said. Li said he is in negotiation with authorities in Jinghe County, where many Ili Pikas were discovered, for the establishment of a nature reserve to keep people away from the rare animals.  In late May, Li led a team of five volunteers to collect video footage from infrared cameras set up last August. Some 30 infrared cameras captured about 16 video clips of the Pika from the two areas over the past 10 months. Li said the video clips showed that pikas communicate with each other through their own urine traces and bodily waste. "They can tell by sniffing whether another pika is nearby. If it is a member of the opposite sex, they find a mate. If it is within its own gender, they claim territory." However, Li didn't find any pikas in the two sites where he spotted and photographed the elusive creature in July last year. He said this doesn't mean there are fewer pikas now as footage from one more area is yet to be collected and the cameras only covered half of the census areas. Yet it still worries him, he said. "We don't know whether it's because the animals didn't come out during the winter, or they were eaten by natural enemies or they died." To collect more accurate and complete information, Li said he plans to buy more infrared cameras with the recently raised money and set them up in all six areas. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/10/asia/china-pika-magic-rabbit-new-risk/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Few people knew about the Ili pika until earlier this year when pictures of China's "magic bunny" went viral. Now, fame is posing more risks. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150323113142-china-ili-pika-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/15/elbagir-freedom-project-young-men-gone.cnn</video>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Iraqi who has seen it all: ISIS in Mosul to stay - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-10 12:25:21</data>
        <autor>Ben Wedeman, CNN International Correspondent</autor>
        <corpo>Baghdad (CNN)We had just finished up our shoot in Al-Makasib Girls' Elementary School in Baghdad's Saadoun neighbourhood and were loading the gear into the car when a man sitting in a wheelchair across the courtyard beckoned to me. "Come, talk to me, too," he said. He introduced himself as Louay Hikmat Shawkat, Iraqi Army veteran of the war with Iran and then the 1991 Kuwait war, refugee from Mosul and a self-described translator of English, French, "Canadian" and "Yugoslavian." Given that the latter two aren't languages, and his English was a tad scratchy, I was intrigued. We were visiting the school to talk to its current "residents" -- 48 Christian families who had fled Mosul when ISIS took over a year ago. Mosul, in northern Iraq and one of the nation's largest cities, is about 405 kilometers (about 250 miles) from the capital of Baghdad. But for these internal refugees, it might as well be a world away. I asked Louay, who is 60, when he thought he might be able to return home.  "Take it out of your mind that ISIS is going to leave Mosul," he insisted, gesturing with his hand as if he were pulling a thread out of his head. The chances he and his wife will someday return to their home in the Mosul suburb of Hamdaniya, he said, are "one in a hundred. One in a million!" Louay said he suffers from diabetes, but he insists on lighting up another cigarette in his nicotine-stained fingers "because I get upset whenever I speak about "Da'ish", the Arabic acronym for ISIS. ISIS, he said, "is an illness. It's impossible to cure. Cancer can be cured, tuberculosis can be cured. Almost every illness can be cured, but not this one." His diabetes causes him to suffer from dizziness whenever he stands up. "If I were well," he vows, "I would go fight them myself." Like everyone else I spoke with at the school, he is desperate to leave Iraq, but his attempts to apply for asylum have come to naught. His last hope, he told me with a mischievous grin, is an old Canadian girlfriend in Montreal.  In the school's makeshift kitchen, I met Linda Jannan, who was busy with the washing up. She fled Mosul with her husband and three children in August, first going to Dohuk, in Iraqi Kurdistan, where they spent six months in a tent in a refugee camp. A thin women in her 30s with the dark circles under her eyes, she also was desperate to leave Iraq. "We are finished," she told me. "Our future, our children, our men have been destroyed. We're too afraid to go out and find work. If only someone outside Iraq will help us find a solution, let us emigrate. We have no hope left." She and her husband had applied to asylum in the United States and Germany, but they were rejected because they have no close relatives in either country. Obama: No 'complete strategy' yet on training Iraqis Over the past few months, these refugees have been visited by a variety of reporters. And it's clear their patience is wearing thin. "What's the point of all this talk?" one man asked me, after declining my request for an on-camera interview. "We talk, we talk, and nothing happens," he snapped. Firyal Abdel Kareem, who was sharing the kitchen with Linda Jannan, is at her wits' end. She spent the winter months in a windy tent in Zakho, near the Turkish border, and is now suffering from Baghdad's sweltering summer heat. "Find a solution for us," she told me, "it's enough. We are tired." "Either they take us out of here, or send us home. Do we have to stay in this school, or in a tent?"  I've been covering Iraq since 1994. I covered the impact of the draconian international sanctions imposed on the country after Iraq's 1990 invasion of Kuwait. I covered the U.S.-led invasion in 2003 and the messy, bloody aftermath. And now I'm back covering the war against ISIS. I'm lucky. I come and go as I please. For the people in this school, there is no such luxury. Thair Al-Naim, his wife and their three young sons left behind a relatively comfortable life in Mosul last summer. He's now penniless and out of work, all his construction equipment seized and sold by ISIS. Speaking to him in the classroom they now call "home," I sense a deep weariness with a life that, for too long, has been fraught with violence and fear. "Since the fall of Saddam," he sighs, "all we've had is war after war, and now we have Da'ish." CNN's Hamdi Alkhshali contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/09/middleeast/iraq-mosul-isis-takeover-anniversary/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>It's been one year since ISIS captured the city of Mosul and thousands of Iraqis have fled the city, but many others still live under the extremists' rule.  CNN's Jomana Karadsheh reports.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/141225215228-01-mosul-fighters-122514-t3-entertainment.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/06/09/iraq-mosul-one-year-after-fall-isis-karadsheh-lok.cnn</video>
        <categoria>middleeast</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Chinese astronaut: We want more cooperation - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-29 03:21:08</data>
        <autor>David McKenzie, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>"Inside Space City," a world exclusive CNN interview with three of China's top astronauts, premieres on Friday May 29 at 11:30 pm ET Beijing (CNN)China wants greater cooperation with other nations in space, particularly the United States, the country's most experienced astronaut has told CNN in an exclusive interview. Fifteen nations including the United States, Russia and Japan cooperate on International Space Station missions, but China's involvement has always been a non-starter because of longstanding resistance from U.S. legislators. INTERACTIVE: IS CHINA WINNING THE SPACE RACE? "As an astronaut, I have a strong desire to fly with astronauts from other countries. I also look forward to going to the International Space Station," Commander Nie Haisheng told CNN. "...Space is a family affair, many countries are developing their space programs and China, as a big country, should make our own contributions in this field." The comments came during a wide-ranging and exclusive interview with the three-person crew of the Shenzhou-10 mission inside Space City, the center of China's space program, near Beijing last month. In 2011, Congress passed an act to bar NASA from having any bilateral contact with individuals of the Chinese space program because of national security fears. "Every time it gets mentioned at all anywhere near Congress, it gets shut down immediately," space analyst Miles O'Brien told CNN. "There is tremendous skepticism there about China. It is viewed as a foe, it is viewed as a government that seeks to take our intellectual property -- our national secrets and treasure." In a white paper released Tuesday, China said that outer space had become an area of "strategic competition." "The Chinese government has always advocated the peaceful use of outer space, it opposes space weaponization and an arms race in outer space. This position will not be changed," Wang Jin, a spokesman for the Ministry of Defense, said. MORE: NASA astronaut: We risk losing out to China  A recent report for the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission said China's improving space capabilities had "negative sum consequences for U.S. military security." But Nie discounted those fears. "The United States and Russia started their space programs early. They are the pioneers," he said. He says foreign astronauts are welcome to visit China's own space station once it is launched. The Chinese expect to finish their space station by 2022 -- around the time International Space Station runs out of funding, potentially leaving China as the only country with a permanent presence in space. China launched its manned space program in 1992. It initially borrowed and bought a great deal of Russian technology, primarily by replicating their Soyuz space craft -- which they dubbed the Shenzhou. But it has been steadily checking off the boxes in manned space flight. In 2003, it put its first man in space. In 2008, it completed its first space walk. And in 2013 Nie and his crew completed the country's longest space mission to date and twice docked with the Tiangong-1 space lab. MORE: Meet the crew of the Shenzhou-10  With support from the highest echelons of the ruling Chinese Communist Party and exceptionally deep pockets, most analysts believe China's space program could become a world leader. "I think in the end -- tortoise versus hare style, they will probably win," said O'Brien. In October last year, China launched its most ambitious unmanned space mission to date: to orbit the moon and then return to Earth. Nicknamed "Xiaofei," or "Little Flyer" on Chinese social networks, the unmanned orbiter traversed 840,000 kilometers on its eight-day mission that saw it round the far side of the moon and take some incredible pictures of Earth and the moon together, the state-run Xinhua news agency reported. It then successfully re-entered the Earth's atmosphere and parachuted down to the surface in Inner Mongolia. Wu Yanhua, vice director of China's State Administration of Science, Technology and Industry for National Defense, said at the time the successful test mission has gathered a lot of experimental data and laid "a solid foundation for future missions." While China hasn't committed to it, many analysts think it wants to put a man on the moon. However, when asked, Commander Nie won't be drawn on whether this is the ultimate goal of the country's space program. "For the next step, the focus is Tiangong-2 and then we will do more preparatory work for the space station." </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/28/asia/china-space-mckenzie/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>CNN's David McKenzie takes a look at the Chinese space program and the simulators used in their training for space missions.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150526153634-china-space-shenzhou-10-crew-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/12/pkg-mckenzie-china-simulation-room.cnn</video>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>YSL ad with 'unhealthily' thin model banned in UK - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-03 14:14:04</data>
        <autor>Mairi Mackay, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>London (CNN)The UK's advertising watchdog has banned an ad for fashion brand Yves Saint Laurent featuring a model who it said was "unhealthily underweight." The Advertising Standards Authority ruled the black-and-white image of a model in a short, black dress and platform high heels was "irresponsible." The ad appeared in Elle UK magazine. The model's pose and the lighting effect drew attention to her rib cage, which was "visible and appeared prominent," the ruling found. The ad also focused on her legs, adding that "her thighs and knees appeared a similar width, and ... looked very thin," especially the "contrast between the narrowness of her legs and her platform shoes," according to the ruling. The ad is the latest in a long line of controversies surrounding the fashion industry's use of thin models, among them the death from anorexia of French model Isabelle Caro following a shocking ad campaign and bans on ultra-skinny models in Israel and France. The UK agency looked into the ad following a complaint from an Elle UK reader. In response to the ruling, Yves Saint Laurent SAS indicated it didn't agree with the view that the model was unhealthily thin "but did not provide a detailed response," the agency said. Both Elle UK magazine and Yves Saint Laurent declined to comment on the ban when CNN reached out to them. A representative from Beat, a UK charity that supports those affected by eating disorders said: "The constant portrayal of a very slender look as the only aspirational ideal for young people needs to be challenged if a generation (is) to grow up with a robust sense of their self-worth." "The ASA ruling is not about whether this person in the picture is healthy, but whether the images of her are being used in a way that can have an irresponsible effect on others, and we are really pleased to see that they are taking action to uphold their responsibility for the social impact of adverts," the rep added. The Advertising Standards Authority said that the ad must not appear again in its current form and called on advertisers to ensure images in their ads were created responsibly. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/06/03/world/skinny-model-yves-saint-laurent-ban/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Yves Saint Laurent advert is banned for showing super skinny model. </descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150603105411-ysl-skinny-model-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/tv/2015/06/03/ysl-skinny-model-advert-ban.cnn</video>
        <categoria>world</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Amanpour joins migrant rescue operation - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-06-16 13:40:38</data>
        <autor>Christiane Amanpour and Dominique van Heerden, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Lampedusa, Italy (CNN)The Italian Navy approached the rickety wooden ship with caution, and a wide berth. Go in too quickly, and the people onboard become so excited about their impending rescue that they capsize by all moving to one side. This is how so many of the drowning disasters have happened. As European leaders decide on measures to tackle the migrant crisis in the Mediterranean, the race to save lives on the high seas goes on, as our CNN team witnessed firsthand. We started our day on a helicopter bound for the frigate Virginio Fasan, one of the Italian Navy's most modern warships, currently in international waters facing the Libyan coast. Along with four other Italian naval vessels they patrol an area of sea about the size of the United Kingdom; some 80,000 square miles. It's a huge effort for the 1,000 men and women continuously at sea, because each rescue takes several hours. Barely 30 minutes into our chopper flight journey the pilot tells us they have spotted a boat, possibly full of migrants. And onboard screens beaming imagery of a wooden vessel packed to the gills confirms their suspicions. The blue boat is on course for Lampedusa, they've completed almost half the journey from Libya 85 miles from where we are... now in international waters the smugglers use their cell phones to call the Italian coast guard for help! That's their MO. The warship Sfinge (Sphinx) is closest, and is promptly dispatched to rescue those onboard. Crew on smaller boats hand out the distinctive orange life vests as soon as they arrive. To get closer and at sea level&#8212;we fly back to the Fasan and get into the ship's speed boat, and watch as navy teams move people to the warship in small groups. All personnel involved in the operation are dressed head to toe in white biohazard suits, face masks and gloves, in case of infectious disease. We're told that in all the crossings not a single case of Ebola has been brought over. The boat has been checked for hostile intent, and once the navy is satisfied they are all migrants, they begin the slow process of off-loading these people and transferring them by their two small boats to the warship. One by one they bring each person up the stairs&#8212;give them a medical, hand out bottles of water, and sit them in rows on the top deck, under the broiling sun. Men are separated from the women and children. One person died, suffocated during the overcrowded boat ride from Libya. Three people had to be medevaced off&#8212;but in all this mission saved 289 lives. They are among 900 who were saved on Wednesday in three different wooden boats, because it was sunny and calm. Most of the migrants saved on this day are from Ethiopia, Sudan, and Eritrea in East Africa, escaping a dictatorial regime and military service that they say amounts to slavery. Almost nobody on board speaks English, but one man tells us his story, saying he left his wife and children over a year ago, and hopes his arrival in Europe will mean he can afford a better life for them back home. And even though he knows a lot of people have died trying to make this dangerous crossing, he tells he was not afraid. "We have one chance, to live or to die," he says. We also talk to 25-year-old Juri, who tells us that God answered their prayers in the form of the Italian Navy. "God is good," she says with a big smile on her face, "they save our lives." UPDATE: On Friday, UNHCR reported that 180 of those rescued had been transferred to four facilities in eastern Sicily. The rest, they say, are still at the port and will be transferred soon. The one fatality was a 17-year-old Eritrean man, who reportedly died of asphyxiation in the hull of the boat. CNN's Mick Krever contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/20/world/amanpour-mediterranean-migrant-rescue/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>The Italian Navy approached the rickety wooden ship with caution, and a wide berth. Go in too quickly, and the migrant boat might capsize by everyone moving to one side.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150521135039-amanpour-mediterranean-15-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/21/pkg-amanpour-mediterranean-migrants.cnn</video>
        <categoria>world</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Photographer documents possessions of Chinese families - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-18 11:26:36</data>
        <autor>Shen Lu, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Beijing (CNN)For more than a decade, Chinese photographer Ma Hongjie has asked dozens of families across the country to empty their homes and pose in front of everything they own. His goal is to tell the stories of those who have been bypassed by China's economic boom -- the people living on the bottom rung of society that haven't enjoyed the fruits of the country's transformation. "The possessions are not even wealth. It's just their lives -- showing how the grassroots try to make a living," said Ma, a photo editor at Chinese National Geography magazine. While the mesmerizing images show a variety of landscapes, lifestyles and cultures, what's most striking is their similarity -- the neatly lined up possessions are mostly daily essentials and tools of trade. Their owners appear proud yet humble. Almost all of Ma's subjects are rural families. He has asked richer families living in cities to participate, but they weren't willing to take part in the project, he said. They possess a lot more, and were afraid of the repercussions of showcasing their wealth, Ma explained. "Yet grassroots were fully at ease showing me whatever they have," he said. "They'd first feel wary about my request, but when I showed the samples they thought it was interesting." Although China now is the second largest economy after the United States, it is also home to the second largest number of poor people in the world, according to the World Bank. Almost 100 million people lived below the national poverty line of $1 a day in 2012.  In his book, which is due to be published later in May, Ma gives the back stories of the families he's photographed. The deepest impression the people he profiled has left upon him is their attitude. Powerless, they never demand anything, Ma said. "Are they satisfied? No. But they have no choice but to accept whatever happens to them," he added. "But they try to live with however little they possess." Although humbling, it also frustrated him. "They suffer from silence." Ma recently revisited the first family he profiled. They lived in a rural town in a mountainous area of Hunan province in southeastern China, back in 2003. To his dismay, nothing had changed in the 10 years since his first visit; their shabby house had become even shabbier, he said. Their sons wanted to get married, but the family couldn't afford to build new homes for them. They had hoped tourism would develop in this old town so that the family would be subsidized for moving out&#8212;then the sons would be able to marry, he said.  Similar stories unfolded everywhere Ma traveled. The Sun family live on boats on the Yellow River that winds through China's heartland. Sun Guiyou, who has been traversing the rivers and lakes for his entire life, says his biggest dream is to one day have a permanent house built on the land. Although the family say they are better off since he first photographed them in 2006, nothing much has changed and they haven't been able to build a home on solid ground. "The way they make a living doesn't change, they are still fishing," he said. "The grandchildren didn't get a good education, or even dropped out of school. You can see them repeating their grandparent's life in the future."  Ma said he was stunned by the diversity of cultures and lifestyles he came across and that it was harrowing to witness these traditions erode. Only a few of the local artisans and performers he met said their offspring were willing to carry on their crafts. Instead, they go to the cities and become migrant workers. When he visited a village in Hainan province in 2010, people lived in small huts. On his return years later, the huts had been replaced by brick and cement dwellings built by the government. In response, the villagers had built new huts next to the government subsidized housing instead, because they were not built in a way that suited their lifestyle. Ventilating smoke from how they cooked meals became difficult in those houses. "The local government thought living in huts was uncivilized, but they were unique," Ma said. "Why should everything be uniform?" The families he documented also shared a hatred of red tape - they bemoaned interference from the local government. So when the government decided to scrap an ancient tradition of taxing farmers for agricultural produce in 2006, farmers and peasants were thrilled by the news. "They simply want to be left alone -- 'Don't make our life so troublesome, let us farm and let us live,' they told me." Ma said. </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/18/asia/china-families-belongings/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>Since 2003, Chinese photographer Ma Hongjie has asked dozens of families across the country to empty their homes and pose in front of everything they own.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150517061017-china-possessions-ma-hongjie-24-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/21/pkg-amanpour-mediterranean-migrants.cnn</video>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Texas hunter bags rhino on controversial Namibia hunt - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-21 20:28:08</data>
        <autor>Ed Lavandera, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Northern Namibia (CNN)In January 2014, Corey Knowlton bid $350,000 for a permit to hunt and kill a black rhino in Namibia. He won the permit and became a target himself. The hunt is now complete. A rhino is dead. This is how it happened.  Windhoek, Namibia -- Knowlton arrived quietly in Namibia to hunt the famed black rhino. Nearly 18 months ago, the Texas hunter bid $350,000 to kill a black rhinoceros in the southern African country of Namibia. The permit was issued by Namibia's Ministry of Environment and Tourism and auctioned by the Dallas Safari Club. Since then, Knowlton has faced scathing criticism and death threats as the world reacted to the controversial hunt of one of the world's most endangered species. Knowlton has spent the last year and a half preparing and planning the hunt that is being highly scrutinized by animal welfare groups around the world. He agreed to let our CNN crew document the hunt. "At this point, the whole world knows about this hunt and I think it's extremely important that people know it's going down the right way, in the most scientific way that it can possibly happen," Knowlton said after arriving in Africa. Knowlton, 36, from Dallas, wants the world to see that the hunt of such a majestic beast on the African continent is not the work of a bloodthirsty American hunter but a vital component of Namibia's effort to save the animal from extinction. Knowlton's $350,000 will go to fund government anti-poaching efforts across the country. And the killing of an older rhino bull, which no longer contributes to the gene pool but which could harm or kill younger males, is part of the science of conservation, he argues. That's why he says he's doing more to save the black rhino than his critics, and why he wanted us along on this historic hunt. Opponents like the International Fund for Animal Welfare have not been swayed, saying hunting as conservation is a bankrupt notion. "We'll simply never agree with that," fund director Azzedine Downes said. "There's a lot of other things that we can and must do in order to protect these animals." The journey of this hunt will examine the emotional debate raging around the issue of how best to protect endangered species on a continent that is home to some of the most legendary animals on the planet. "I think people have a problem just with the fact that I like to hunt," Knowlton said. "I want to see the black rhino as abundant as it can be. I believe in the survival of the species."  Northern Namibia -- The hunt sets off with a sunrise flight to the region of Namibia where Knowlton will track a black rhino. There's a great deal of concern about news coverage of the hunt in Namibia. We've been told that when our reports are broadcast around the world that Namibian government officials fear poaching syndicates will use the information to identify the location of other black rhinos. For that reason, we have agreed not to report the specific locations of the hunt. According to animal conservationists, there are approximately 5,000 black rhinos in the wild worldwide today, 2,000 of them in Namibia. Hentie van Heerden is a professional hunter hired by the Namibian government to guide Knowlton on the highly scrutinized hunt of the black rhino. Van Heerden, 40, has an international clientele, mostly from Europe, who come to hunt wild game and the exotic animals of Africa. He was born in Namibia and grew up hunting. The thorn-infested terrain in the north of the country does not faze him. He wears sandals even when he hunts the wildest of animals. The bearded van Heerden has the dry sense of humor of a skilled hunter teaching a journalist what to do if we are to stare down a charging rhino. "The aim is to get out of its way without him flattening you," he said. "It's very rare that they come back for seconds and if that is the case, you have to get some more out of its way." Van Heerden says there are a few critics of the black rhino hunt in Namibia, but most people here embrace a culture of hunting. "There will always be activists and that's how they make their money," he said. "They have no clout here in Namibia, because people understand hunting." The hunt is sanctioned and monitored by Namibia's Ministry of Environment and Tourism. It has identified 18 black rhinos across the country that meet the criteria for being hunted and eliminated. The rhino must be an older rhino that is no longer reproducing and is considered a threat to younger, healthier rhinos. Rhinos are intensely territorial and will often kill each other in gruesome fights. Knowlton is targeting one of four black rhinos at the top of the government list, the ones considered "high priority threats to the herd." But identifying these rhinos in the dense brush and in the heat of a dangerous hunt makes Knowlton uneasy, though he will have the help of local trackers and guides. "If it charges at us and we are already sure it's the right one, we are going to kill it," Knowlton said. "If we aren't sure if it's the right one, we are going to try and get out of the way. If we don't feel like we can get out of the way, we got to kill it." That would be the worst-case scenario for Knowlton. For him, the rhino hunt must be carried out flawlessly.  Northern Namibia -- Just after sunrise, Knowlton arrives at a watering hole hidden deep in the Namibian brush to start the hunt. Two government trackers have spotted signs of a rhino heading away from the water. The footprint appears fresh. The weathered wrinkles of the rhino's hide are still visible in the print. The intricate details in the sand suggest the tracks are just a few hours old. The government tracker says, based on the footprints, he can tell this animal is probably one of the black rhinos Knowlton has been permitted to hunt, and that the animal is probably no more than 5 miles away. This is where the hunt begins. The trackers move quickly through the thorny bush and tall grasses. They rarely speak. Quick hand signals are all they need to show the path to follow. Silence is vital when you're tracking a black rhino. The hunting party winds its way through the brush. The rhino's footprints suggests the nearly 3,000 pound (1,360 kilogram) beast is meandering, which tells the hunters it does not feel threatened. As the heat of the day intensifies, rhinos will usually find shady areas to take quick naps. The ranger from the ministry who is observing and leading the trackers says the hunting party is gaining ground on the rhino. But the brush is so dense. Knowlton worries that we could stumble across the rhino at any moment and end up face to face. "I think people think of it as this docile thing," Knowlton said of his prey. "But you are dealing with an extremely athletic animal that can do whatever it wants to you very quickly." The only sounds are the brushes and scrapes of the hunting party cutting through the thorn-infested bushes of this terrain. It seems like every bush has wicked thorns that rip across our skin and clothing. Rhinos have an intense sense of smell and hearing that alerts them to danger from hundreds of yards away. The winds are swirling in the early afternoon hours and the tracker says the rhino can probably sense our presence and is moving away quickly. Knowlton is more concerned with something else. He's been told there are three rhinos known to inhabit the area he's in, but the Namibian government has only authorized the hunting of two of them. Visibility in the brush around us is down to about 15 feet (4.6 meters.) Knowlton is worried that if the rhino charges through the thick brush that he would only have a split second to decide whether to take the shot. It's becoming too risky. We've spent five hours trekking nearly 6 miles through the brush when Knowlton and his hunting partner decide to call it a day. Killing the wrong rhino, Knowlton said, would be a catastrophic mistake. Last year, one of Knowlton's critics suggested the trophy hunting of a black rhino was like shooting a couch in a living room. This criticism annoys Knowlton endlessly. He's quick to bring it up with a heavy dose of sarcasm. "So this is just like hunting a couch? Give me a break," he said. "This isn't easy. It's brutal."  On the road to southern Namibia -- Knowlton decides the hunt in the north is too treacherous. The brush is dense and visibility low. That's a dangerous combination for the hunting party and Knowlton knows that killing the wrong rhino will make him an even bigger target of international outrage. He and his hunting guide decide to drive to southern Namibia to target another dangerous black rhino that lives in a region with better visibility. But on the way we hear that rhino has died, probably of natural causes.  Northern Namibia -- Knowlton returns to the region that makes him the most nervous. And on this morning, the trails are not strong. The trackers have trouble finding prints leading away from the watering holes where the rhinos drink vast amounts of water. It's clear the rhino hunt will not end today.  Northern Namibia -- The morning starts with a startling discovery. Knowlton's professional hunting guide has discovered a camera image showing a rhino at a remote watering hole just before sunrise. The image is stunning. The rhino is more massive than I expected. Its horn is long with a lethal pointed tip. Knowlton spots a large gash in the rhino's ear. It's a crucial identifying mark that tells him instantly this rhino is on the approved government list to be hunted. The hunting party quickly picks up the tracks and disappears into the vicious African bush. The rhino footprints are fresh and light on the sand, telling the trackers the animal is slowly walking, eating grass and taking naps in the shade to avoid the rising sun. Today feels different. There's a sense that just beyond our view we are close to the rhino. The hunting party stops to drink water in the shade of a tree for 20 minutes. When the tracking resumes, Knowlton discovers the spot where the rhino had been resting not moments earlier. You can see the imprint of its wrinkled hide still fresh on the sandy ground. The rhino is close. Knowlton's hands firmly grip his high-powered 500 Nitro Express rifle. Moments later, I see a massive flash of gray leap up over the bushes some 50 feet in front of us. It disappears and you can't tell which direction the rhino is running. It's jarring to see this close how quickly these massive creatures can move. I remember the advice van Heerden, the professional hunting guide, gave me the day before. "You can't outrun the rhino," he said. "If it means to dive into a thorn bush to the left or to the right, we need to get out of its way in a big hurry." Now we can't see the rhino, but we know it's close. Van Heerden tells Knowlton, "He's angry. The next time he will charge." Twenty minutes later as the hunting party moves through the brush, I hear a sound I've not heard before during our trek. The rhino is moving around but it's invisible. It's impossible to grasp how such a beast can move like a ghost in the brush. The hunting party moves single file through a tree line. As the last member of the group emerges, he looks to his left and no more than 40 feet away the rhino is there, staring straight at us. "There it is!" says the last member in the group. It's a breathtaking sight. But this isn't the time to stand and stare. I cut to one side and the rhino starts charging in my direction. "Ed! Get down!" shouts van Heerden. I rush behind Knowlton and his hunting guide. "As soon as you dropped below my gun, I could see the whole animal right behind you," Knowlton would tell me later. I turn around and for a quick flash only see the top half of the rhino in front of us. Then four shots explode through the air. The rhino has been hit at least three times. The hunting party then makes the final push to find the rhino. I've lost track of time. This last push might have taken 30 minutes, it might have taken an hour. It was an incredibly emotional experience. A tracker climbs into a tree and spots the rhino in an open field about 100 yards away. Knowlton gets into position and fires the final shots. The black rhino is dead. Knowlton walks up from behind the rhino and when he's certain it's over, he kneels next to it. "Any time you take an animal's life it's an emotional thing," Knowlton said. The Namibian government official assures Knowlton it is the rhino on the approved hunting list. The trackers smile with relief and shake hands. I ask Knowlton if he still feels that killing this black rhino was the right thing to do and that it will benefit the future of this endangered species. "I felt like from day one it was something benefiting the black rhino," Knowlton reflected just moments after the hunt ended. "Being on this hunt, with the amount of criticism it brought and the amount of praise it brought from both sides, I don't think it could have brought more awareness to the black rhino." WATCH: Rhino hunter defends killing an endangered animal READ: Rhino horns more valuable than gold WATCH: Rhino gets armed guards WATCH: Getting rhinos back to Uganda CNN's Jason Morris contributed to this report.</corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/africa/namibia-rhino-hunt/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>CNN's&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/profiles/ed-lavandera-profile"&gt; Ed Lavandera reports&lt;/a&gt; from Namibia, Africa on an American hunter who tracked down and killed an endangered black rhino.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519125557-rhino-corey-knowlton-large-169.jpg</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/19/erin-dnt-lavandera-namibia-black-rhino-hunt.cnn</video>
        <categoria>africa</categoria>
    </noticia>
    <noticia>
        <titulo>Traitors no more? North Korean defectors 'forgiven' - CNN.com</titulo>
        <data>2015-05-20 03:45:20</data>
        <autor>Tim Schwarz, CNN</autor>
        <corpo>Pyongyang, North Korea (CNN)Kkot-jebi -- literally "flower swallows" -- sounds poetic, but the reality is much harsher. The North Korean term refers to homeless children, fending for themselves without the support of family or state. The word traces it roots back to the aftermath of the Korean War, an imaginative pronunciation of the Russian word "kochevyi," meaning "wandering," and referring to those displaced by the 1950-53 conflict. During the 1990s, North Korea was hit by several years of famine as disastrous harvests laid waste to the land, killing hundreds of thousands, according to conservative estimates. The country's social safety net was reduced to tatters. Families fell apart. And flower swallows re-emerged in large numbers. Although conditions today are much better, North Korea remains desperately poor. Food is in short supply for a large portion of the population -- and kkot-jebi are still very much in existence.  North Korea is one of the most secretive societies in the world. When a CNN team recently visited, our entire schedule was arranged by our official government hosts. Our "minders" accompanied us on every shoot. We had put in certain requests, but we never knew more than a few hours in advance what the next item on our itinerary would be. When we were told to go to a meeting room at our hotel one afternoon, we had no idea who was going to be behind the doors, just something to do with the reality of defectors. When we walked through the doors and saw eight young people sitting on one side of a huge round conference table, we immediately knew who we were to meet.  In early summer 2013, the world's media cried foul over the repatriation of a group of nine North Korea children, then aged between 14 and 19, from Laos. They had been picked up by border security as they were being smuggled from China into Laos by South Korean missionaries, in the hope of getting them resettled in South Korea. READ: Agonizingly close to freedom Pyongyang is not shy about its hatred of defectors. It refers to them in official media as "human scum" and accuses them of criminal acts, lying about their own country for fame and money and abandoning their own families. The decision to return the children was widely condemned. Dire predictions were made about their fate: The children were being sent back to prison; they would face a lifetime of retribution and could even be executed. But here in this room, nearly two years after their return, these former kkot-jebi appear transformed. Four young men dressed in the blue blazers of university students and two boys and two girls in secondary school uniforms, all sat waiting to answer our questions. The ninth member of the group was in a university further away from Pyongyang and could not be brought in at short notice.  They were all children between the ages of 12 and 17 when they crossed into China, separately or in small groups. They only met after they arrived at the missionaries' house. We asked why they left -- it was an uncomfortable opening question. "We were young," said 17-year-old Ri Gwang Hyok. "We just went to China for fun." Pressed for more detail, Mun Chol, 21, admitted: "Frankly, we had some family difficulties. We had been through a period in our history we call 'the arduous march (the years of famine).' We were not living well. I was young and naive. We were living by the Amnok river, which is at the border. I meant to return home. I was curious." We then asked how many of them had experienced hunger before they left. Four of the eight raised their hands. "It was winter. We had preserved food during autumn. But it wasn't enough. Our family was too large," explained Pak Kwang Hyok, 19. Once in China, the children were brought to a house in the border town of Dandong, looked after by a South Korean missionary CNN has called M.J. in previous reports, along with his wife. There, according to M.J., the starving children were transformed. According to the youngsters now, the picture was not so rosy. They said they were kept in the house for a year and a half. "The missionary lectured us about freedom," recalled Mun Chol. "But we weren't given any freedom. He forced us to study God and memorize religious books. "Of course, the food was good," he added, "but that was our only pleasure. When you have food things seem OK, but a kid needs more than that." Following our encounter with the students, CNN contacted M.J., who asked about their well-being. He says he misses them. While hesitant to say much out of fear for their safety, he insists the students needed his help after fleeing North Korea.  China is a historical ally of North Korea, and North Koreans found illegally in the country face deportation if caught. After a year and a half, the missionary decided to move the children to a third country. He chose Laos, on China's southwestern border, from where he hoped he could get them to South Korea. After a harrowing night trek for four hours through the hilly border region, the party were picked up by Laotian police and detained. When they were told they would be sent back to North Korea they were terrified. "The missionary said we would be killed if we went back," said Mun Chol. "He told us our families had been killed because we had left our homes."  But instead of being punished, they tell us they received special treatment, extra tuition to make up for three years of missed schooling, and are now studying in the best educational establishments in the capital. "I was scared," admitted Pak Gwang Hyok. "I had left my home with a guilty conscience and spent time abroad. We had betrayed our country. I thought we would be punished. But now we are studying in the best universities in Pyongyang. Our fears were pretty foolish." Soon after their return, the children appeared on North Korean television to denounce their enticement to defect by South Koreans. Now , more than a year later, they are again on display. They have become poster children for the "benevolence and forgiveness" of the North Korean authorities. There is a huge difference between their lives when they left for China and now. "I feel like a pauper who has become a prince," said Ri Gwang Hyok. But their families have not joined them in Pyongyang, the showcase capital. They remain in the poor border areas and their lives have not changed. When he thinks about what might have happened if he had made it to South Korea, Mun Chol said, "If I had made it, I could have become a traitor -- a bad guy who deserts his family. "I could have gone down in history as one of the 'scum of the earth.'" READ: North Korean: I felt like a slave in Kuwait </corpo>
        <urlPagina>http://edition.cnn.com/2015/05/19/asia/north-korean-child-defectors-revisited/index.html</urlPagina>
        <descricao>In an exclusive interview with CNN's Paula Hancocks, one of the highest-level defectors from North Korea says leader Kim Jong Un's cruelty is turning insiders against him.</descricao>
        <imagem>http://i2.cdn.turner.com/cnnnext/dam/assets/150519153632-north-korea-pak-quote-large-169.png</imagem>
        <video>http://edition.cnn.com/videos/world/2015/05/12/pkg-hancocks-north-korea-kim-jong-un-power.cnn</video>
        <categoria>asia</categoria>
    </noticia>
</noticias>